I
don't know.
Hey,
hey, hey.
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Welcome Living Mana Church family. We're
so happy that you are here with us. We
apologize for being late. We can't even
say it was technical difficulties. It
was me.
Some things were happening outside of my
control though is so that is why we are
late today. So, we do apologize for
that. We're so happy that you are here.
Please put in the chat where you are
viewing from. I hope you did enjoy. I
see somebody did enjoy the the love
trivia. Today is the what the world
likes to say, the love day. Um I like to
show my husband love every single day,
but this is the day that the world tends
to at least here in America tends to
highlight. So we are going to be taking
some of your questions that you have
sent in about love, about marriage,
about relationships, even being single.
We're here for for all of it. We're
going to share a little bit about our
story just a little bit. Um so that um
hopefully it it can maybe help some who
who are listening. But yeah, some of you
are already putting in the chat. Uh we
have Wendy from Idaho. Welcome. Please
continue to put in the chat where you're
viewing from. Audience, welcome
everyone. I will try to get to those um
as we can, but because we're behind, I
can't spend as much time as I normally
do. Um, but yeah, please put in the chat
where you're viewing from. And if this
is your very first time, always good to
see you, Veronica from Washington State.
But if this is your very first time,
please put a one in the chat so you can
learn a little bit more about Living
Mana Church. But again, we are very
happy that you are here. And as you are
putting in the chat, we are going to
vote to bring to or bring somebody into
official membership. And we are also
going to um do a first reading of
somebody who wants to become an official
member here at Living Mana Church. All
right. So, we have
we have we have we have
um
some membership transfers that I need to
find. And while you're looking for that,
um I do want to say that uh today's
sermon is actually going is actually
called a love story.
>> And um
>> uh so kind of in line with what we're
going to be talking about in Sabbath
school.
>> Um some of you may have heard well that
that title may sound familiar to to you
because um I preached a sermon on this
many years ago
>> on the book of Revelation.
Um, but that is not the love story that
we're going to be talking about today.
This is going to be actually something
totally different.
>> So, you're going to be preaching about
me like
>> but
um this is uh you will be blessed by
this message
>> uh for sure as you listen to this
biblical
love story that is uh absolutely
mind-blowing. So, um, make sure that you
all, uh, you know,
>> we will be listening.
>> Stay tuned. Stay locked in.
>> We will definitely still be listening.
Okay. So, we we're excited about that.
But we have a second reading. Um,
>> okay. Let's see. We have a second
reading for
uh Jason Diggs from Cantoen View 7th Day
Adventist Church, and he's wanting to
transfer into
>> Living Man of Church. And this is the
first reading for Michael Britt from the
McDonald Road 7th Day Adventist Church
in McDonald, Tennessee.
>> Okay. So,
>> the Brit family, I'm Yes. And we're
happy about that. We're excited about
that.
>> Um, and then we have a uh Oh, kind of
sad because some people are transferring
out, but we always know there's reasons
why people have to transfer out to like
a brickandmortar church. Uh, but we have
Darius Ziggler and John Ziggler and
they're transferring from LMOC to Tri
City 7th Day Adventist Church in
Prattville, Alabama. I don't know where
Prattville is, but
>> it is somewhere here in Alabama where we
are too. So, we need to vote for our
second for Jason Diggs.
>> Okay.
>> Transferring in and the other ones will
get and that's the second
>> that's the only second reading we have
is for Jason Digs.
>> Okay. So, we're going to entertain a
motion for Jason Diggs. Um, and we'll
wait for that in the chat. So, we need a
motion and we need a second.
And um, as of waiting for that, I just
remembered we should probably talk about
uh what our members are getting now.
>> Yeah, I know. But maybe
>> not not not fully.
>> Okay.
>> But just uh,
>> okay, let's vote.
>> So, we got a motion.
>> Um, and uh, we have a second. We'll
count one of those as a second and then
we'll go ahead and vote. All in favor of
welcoming Jason Diggs into the
fellowship of the Living Man of 7day
Adventist Church
>> as an official member.
>> Um please put a one in the chat.
>> One for me.
>> Amen.
>> Yes.
>> All right.
So, the ones are coming in.
Um,
yeah. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> There they go. Amen. Amen.
>> Um, all right. So, um, Jason, it is
official. It has passed. You are uh
officially a member of uh Living 7
Adventist Church. We welcome you. And um
let me let me just take a take a couple
minutes.
>> No, take
>> one minute.
>> 60 seconds and then we have to get to
Sister Anne and then we got to get into
this school.
>> Okay. So, um some of you have heard uh
about the photo theology Bible software
uh that I launched a few uh months ago
now. And uh we just had something, you
know, special happen. This is
specifically for our members. If you are
a member,
>> an official member of member
>> on the books
>> on the books.
>> We love you viewing audience. We love
you audience, but this is for you have
to be an official member.
>> We love you faith members as well. But
if you are a member of living mana, you
uh we have a space on the on the uh
photo theology
uh uh Bible study software that is
specifically a living mana church space.
So basically it is like having your own
our own kind of like a Bible study
Facebook
>> community on a living man. So
>> yeah and and you have access to the
software to do Bible study to create
Bible studies
>> to lead out in Bible studies create
devotionals.
>> It would take an hour to explain
everything you can do on the app.
>> Yeah. And we were actually on last night
and it took two hours. I didn't realize
that we were on for two hours last
night. I don't think anybody else did.
Uh yeah, sorry for the discrimination,
Kitty. I'm sorry, but um there's a
reason.
>> You can be a member. Anybody's welcome
to be a member.
>> Anybody's no discrimination here.
>> Yes.
>> Come and join.
>> Um yeah, we were actually on for two
hours last night talking about all that
could be done on this software. Um,
and so if you're a member, if you are a
member,
>> you have access to this for free.
>> Yes. So, an email should have gone out
to you uh yesterday and the day before.
Um, you should be able to go to the site
uh and just put your email in, create an
account, and it should recognize your
email and give you immediate access not
only to the living manace, but to the
entire app. Um, so if you did not get
I'm gonna say if you did not get an
email,
>> um, then
>> just contact Sister Patrice if you
didn't get an email and then we'll make
sure that you get the information that
is needed. So go to your email, you'll
get all the information.
>> That's a good That's a good close.
>> Yep.
>> All right.
>> Good.
>> This is a real bless. I will say we're
going to talk about we'll do a whole on
it, but we're just trying to let you
guys know that that's happening. you'll
get more information from us here um as
as as the weeks and time go on. But it's
definitely a blessing if you're a member
to get that for sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Um it's a wonderful tool for Bible
study. And
>> yeah, and if you're if you're a member
and you happen to be in a 7-day trial,
don't worry about that. You you have
access. So, just let me know if you have
an issue and we'll we'll get it
>> taken care of.
>> All right.
>> All right. If you guys really knew what
you just got, I'd see a lot of hands
doing this like phrase, but you'll see.
You'll come back with hands up in the
air. Okay.
>> Um,
Sister Anne, we want to welcome Sister
Anne. She is giving the ministry
spotlight position today. So, we want to
welcome
our amazing
Hi, welcome.
>> Good afternoon.
>> Good to see you here. tell us tell us
and the audience
>> what ministry you're leading out in and
what you would like to share.
>> Well, I'm leading out in two ministries
and that's going to be uh benevolence
and then small groups.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but more specifically today I just
want to talk about something brand new
that just happened with um benevolence
and we definitely want to share that. If
I can just squeeze in 30 seconds to say
this. Yes,
>> about the app. A few weeks ago, there
was a person who reached out to me on
Mighty. We are friends on Mighty and she
asked me if I had an opport if I was
available to talk to her. She was in a
really, really, really bad place
>> and I didn't see her message initially.
Um, so she had to kind of wait until I
saw the message and then reach back out.
And she told me while she was waiting
for me to get the message, pastor, I
told her to send me the actual video so
I can get it to you. Um, but she said
while she was waiting on me to get back
to her, she started playing around with
your app
>> and some kind of way, she was having
this conversation with the app and the
app um asked her to sing a song that was
on her heart or something and she
remembered this song that she sang many
years ago. She's a beautiful she sings
such a Oh, she's beautiful
uh singer, right?
>> Yeah. and she had a chance to sing this
song to the app.
>> And so when I by the time I called
>> I think I think she shared the lyrics.
She wrote the lyrics down and shared it.
Yeah.
>> Yep.
>> It it was amazing. I mean if you heard
it you would be like you need to be in
the studio, right?
>> Um but my point is the app really did
the app was app
>> on her behalf. And so it was it was a
tremendous blessing.
>> Praise God. Um, by the time I talked to
her, her whole demeanor had changed. She
was she was doing great
>> um just for having that interaction with
the app. So, take advantage of it.
>> Amen.
>> Praise God.
>> Yes.
>> So, yes. Okay.
>> So,
>> just want to get up.
>> Yeah. Sister an just someone is just
asking how if they can get access to the
app any other way. And yes, everyone can
get access to the app. Um, but there is
a a special thing for the Living Mana
Church.
>> Well, there's a cost members. Yeah, the
members can get
>> to get the app. So, there's a cost if if
you're not an official member. Yeah. But
>> and we will
>> we'll we'll address that at another
time.
>> Yeah. We're going to actually do a
Sabbath school about the app and using
the app and showing you all the amazing
things and how it can really enhance
your Bible study. But this is not it.
>> That is not it.
>> That is not today. That'll probably be
next week.
>> Yep.
>> Okay. All right, Sister Anne. So,
>> yes, we want to hear from you, Sister
An. We always love when you share and
all of your um
>> I just love your charisma and your
personality, Sister Anne. I just love
your creativity. It's always fun to see
what you're going to come up with. So, I
just Yeah. But we're excited to hear
what you would like to share today with
us and with our audience.
>> So, here's the deal. I was talking two
or three days ago with Sister Gigi.
We're just talking about other projects
and I don't even know remember how it
came up. I just happen to say uh we have
to do something for people who don't
have laptops because there's this one
person who's behind on her homework
assignment as El Moses because she
doesn't have a laptop. And so I said,
and I'm not trying to start, you know,
we're just chatting, right? I'm like,
I'm not trying to start another whole
ministry, but it's just something we
need to do. I don't know what. And so
Gigi says, "Well,
how about we have a laptop drive?"
And she says, "I have an extra laptop
here." And watch this. Y'all know I like
my I like to do my visual aids, right?
>> I have another laptop home, too. And
it's a nice one. It's just sitting And
so we're going to donate our laptops to
LMOC.
We want to get those laptops and this is
being sponsored, if you will, by um the
benevolence department um some kind of
way. And we're still in the planning
process, but we have recruited our very
own tech person. We're going for those
who want to donate a laptop, if you have
an extra one, you're going to we're
going to have eventually we're going to
have a mailing address. you mail it
there. Then from there, it's going to go
to our tech person who's going to wipe
it clean and reset it to all the
manufacturers original settings and then
we're going to ship it out to the person
who needs it. So, first and foremost, we
want to uh be a blessing to those that
are serving in um in Living Mana who
need a laptop and don't have one and of
course the students here at Living Mana.
Um and so maybe we are planning to do
the laptop drive a couple of times a
year to help people. So uh it's just an
opportunity and this is how small groups
and ministry start just having that
dialogue and wanting to bless God's
people. So don't take for granted when
you have those light bulb moments. Like
if you want to bless some people, pick
up the phone, text somebody, we'll help
you put together a plan. Let's make it
happen because uh time is short and we
want to just bless people as much as we
can.
>> Amen.
>> Amen. That's that sounds amazing. That
sounds amazing. I honestly I'll be
honest with the audience. I mean, we
always say this is real. This is not
performance. So, be honest. I was like,
"Oh, what is Sister Anne gonna talk
about?" I had no idea what it was. I
thought you were going to talk about
what, like you said, you lead out in,
you know, you're the head of the benev
benevolence committee. you also lead out
um in another small group. So I thought,
"Oh, she's going to share about that,
but I just wasn't sure." And then when
you mentioning this, I'm like, "Oh, wow.
This is amazing. This is absolutely
amazing." So
>> just having a conversation.
>> Yes.
>> And now we have a whole thing.
>> Yes. And so you did did you mention how
they can what they need to do if that's
the case that they do need a laptop to
>> That's good. Good idea.
>> Would they reach out to you on mighty
networks or how would what would they
do? Yes,
>> reach out to me on Mighty Networks at
some point in the next few weeks. Um,
the benevolence department is going to
have space on Mighty. Um, we're going to
have some very specific instructions. We
I'll probably reach out and chat with
some people who say they may need a
laptop, get the details. We're still
kind of putting it all together and
trying to figure out what makes sense,
but it is coming. So, if you you can
also email me directly at angela.perry
livinga.urch, church, but you can also
reach me, of course, on Mighty as well.
I'm on Mighty pretty much all day, every
day.
>> Yes. And for those of you who don't know
what Mighty Networks is, you'll hear
more about that at the beginning of the
divine worship. But that is great. Uh,
Sister Anne, thank you for sharing. This
was an amazing um idea that uh you and
Sister Gigi came up with together. So,
that that this is a great this is
wonderful. So, uh, we just pray that God
will bless it and many will be blessed
and be able to to connect with these
refurbished laptops that they're going
to be getting that are going to be a
complete blessing. A complete blessing.
>> Absolutely.
>> All right. Um, speaking of that, I think
there's an extra laptop. I think we have
I think we might be part of it. Okay.
>> Okay. All right. Well, thank you again.
Thank you, sister.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> And we want to go into our Sabbath
school. um for today and um we're
praying that God will bless it. So,
let's let's let's pray.
>> Let's pray. T-shirt message.
>> Oh, thank you. T-shirt message. How
could I?
>> But seek first his kingdom.
>> Can you see it? It kind of goes down
there.
>> And and his righteousness, and all these
things shall be added unto you, which is
a verse in my message today.
>> I love how we the Holy Spirit connects
us together. Um so yeah so we know that
this is Matthew for those who don't know
this is Matthew chapter 6 verse 33 and
it is such a powerful um message for us
to be reminded all the time that we need
to seek God first in everything. So
seeking God first like be like there was
always times where I thought oh seeking
God first means you know make sure you
have like say a prayer first thing in
the morning do your devotion first thing
in the morning just like or seeking
in that way but
the re the way this has touched me and I
think I've shared something like this
similar with this message is um seeking
God first
before you allow yourself to experience
Well, to to go deep into fear, like you
might feel an emotion of fear, but seek
God first when you feel that fear, when
you feel anxious when you're feeling sad
and depressed. Seek him first. Seek him
first when you're feeling
>> angry or you're having an emotion, a
negative emotion or whatever. Of course,
seek him first when you need to make a
decision about something. Like, go to
God first. Don't just make a decision.
Pray to him. But the way that it was
speaking to me now is just
before you allow yourself to be
overwhelmed by emotions and I'm losing
my voice.
Allow seek him first. Turn to him first.
>> Just never try to do this life alone.
And that's by moment by moment, day by
day. Don't try to do this thing by
yourself. Seek God. Seek God. Seek God.
He wants to walk this life with us.
>> Um so yeah.
>> Amen. That's the That's the t-shirt
message for today.
>> Amen.
>> All right. So, now you can pray.
>> No, let's pray.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, heavenly father, we thank you, Lord,
for this Sabbath day, Lord. We're asking
that you would please be with us, Lord,
as we worship you. We pray that you
would uh be with us as we uh talk about
our relationships, Lord. And we just
pray a blessing upon uh those who are
watching, those who are listening. Um
those who are in relationships, those
who have left relationships, those who
are getting ready to enter into
relationships, Lord, um just uh allow
today's message both in the Sabbath
school uh and even the divine service,
Lord,
um speak to speak to us all about the
power of love. And uh we pray this in
Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen. All right. We do have
questions that have been sent in and you
may pop some up on the screen, but today
he's not taking well, we'll take Bible
questions if it's pertaining to
relationship, love, not if and it' be
Revelation or Daniel if it's talking
about love, but no, we're not doing
anything. He's not taking the regular
Bible questions today. And we're talking
about um marriage, relationships, being
single, just love. So, um I think uh we
do have questions, but I think we've
never and this is going to be the real
fast version of like um our testimony.
It's not really this is just a little
snippet. It's not even going to be
because we don't have time for all of
that. But,
>> um just to encourage you guys too um
just to know that there's somebody out
if you're not in a relationship
>> um and you're still looking, just know
that seeky first. Yeah.
>> Seek ye first and God will provide uh
that person for you.
>> A good person for you.
>> He will provide the person that he wants
for you. I truly believe that.
>> Um
>> a good person.
>> A good person.
>> Yeah.
>> Of course.
>> A caring person.
>> A the only thing that God provides.
>> A thoughtful person.
>> A thoughtful person. Like let's say
there's a lady in a hospital who's h who
has a husband named Gary Benson and uh
you know she's in a hospital but he's
watching and he he he
is so thoughtful that he's like hey my
wife is in the hospital she's watching
shout her out
>> and say happy Valentine's Day for
>> tell her happy Sabbath tell her just
>> happy Sabbath what's her name
>> tell her well I didn't see it but I just
saw Michael Benson saying I
Gary Benson saying,
>> "Hey, my wife is in the hospital. Shout
her out." So, that's a that's a
thoughtful husband.
>> That is a very thoughtful husband. And
Gary's wife, I'm so happy that you're
still watching us and you're in the
hospital. I'm sorry. We will pray for
you. Um, and that you healing for
healing for you and whatever you're
going through. But that was a very
thoughtful thing.
>> Michaela, it's Michaela.
>> Michaela.
>> Okay. Well, welcome Michaela. We welcome
to Living Man Church. I'm so happy that
you're here. Even though you're in the
hospital, we're praying for you. Let's
just take a quick second to pray for
Michaela. Let's take Okay.
>> Heavenly Father, Lord, uh we just ask
that you be with Michaela. Um thank you
for Gary being such a thoughtful
husband. Uh but you understand what why
Michaela's in the hospital. Just heal
her. Work everything out. Bring peace to
Gary and Michaela um for this situation.
And we ask all these things in Jesus
name. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> All right. That was a very very sweet
thing. Very kind. very thoughtful
>> and I know this sounds like random but
it just her being in the hospital just
reminded me of what happened yesterday
with the lady in the hospital.
>> Yes. And then and brother Terry was able
to have a great conversation with her.
So
>> yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> That was that was very random and they
don't know what we're talking about. So
>> they don't but I'm going to tell them
real quickly.
>> Okay. Tell them real quick
>> because we were um I was actually put I
don't know if I was putting together my
sermon or what. And anyone have Nextdoor
Neighbor?
>> It's called Nextdoor Neighbor.
>> It's called Next Door Neighbor. Just a
local community.
>> Local community, but it's everywhere,
>> right? And they usually tell you, "Oh,
my dog's lost or somebody there's been a
fire over here." Just kind of keeps your
community connected.
>> Yeah. So, I'm never really on there, but
yesterday I just got this message that
Yeah. I'm I'm not on there at all, but
sometimes I'll get messages that pop up.
>> And there was a message from a
63year-old lady who was saying, "Hey, I
have multiple scerosis." And I think
that's what caught my attention.
>> Okay.
>> She said, "I have multiple scerosis. Um,
I'm in a nursing home and I feel like
God has left me. Um,
>> and you know, I don't have any family.
>> If anybody could reach out to me,
>> Yeah.
>> I would so appreciate it. and she put
her number in
>> the uh
>> in the in the on the the next door
neighbor
>> on next door neighborh
>> and um so I saw it and I said I'm going
to reach out to her and I actually sent
it to uh Terry
>> to Terry and Amra as well
>> and because I was you know putting my
sermons together and and whatever
whatever by the time last night
>> by the evening Terry was talking to her
>> they were talking and she's actually in
um Huntsville in Huntsville she's here
so We're hope we're going to meet we we
will meet her. We will meet her.
>> But uh she's not far. Terry and Emma
were able to spend
>> I think they said like an hour or
something
>> talking
>> talking and praying with her and uh it
was just a powerful
>> uh I think testimony.
>> Yes.
>> Of of uh God's love.
>> God's love. Yes.
>> That you would see it.
When I say he's never I' he's never I
mean when we lived in our old community
I think I went on there once when I was
looking was something had to do with the
community but I didn't even know that
you it was even on your radar.
>> So yeah that was God's love for her
>> put her like allowed him to see it and
now we're and he now she's on Living Man
Church's radar. So we're going to
>> we're going to do all that we can do to
extend God's love to her. So, speaking
of love,
>> yes, let's get to
>> I don't even know if we really have too
much time. So, this is going to be the
quickest um thing. So, like put in your
chat and we're going to get to some of
your questions that you guys have
emailed in. So, we do have those. Um but
just again reminding you this is just to
say
our love story, God was just
orchestrating things. um making sure
that we actually met and connected
because as you guys know he was in the
music industry doing his thing. God
moved on his heart. He comes out of the
music industry doesn't really know which
way God is leading him in direction. Um
I'm at that same time I'm at Oakwood
College at the time. Um
in my senior year about to graduate,
graduate and just get this overwhelming
emotion that I need to stay put instead
of I had gotten job offers to go to New
York City. Um good job offers and I but
I felt the Holy Spirit very heavily and
I have to say I had been converted like
really converted in that last six
months. Mhm.
>> So I had like a really
>> uh what do I want to say real
sensitivity to the Holy Spirit.
>> So I knew when the Holy Spirit was like
h no.
>> So that was 199
>> 97
>> 97 that you had your conversion
experience.
>> I had had it it started in 96 but it
really took a a a huge turn at the
beginning of 97.
>> Yeah. So, um, so I I actually stayed
here in Huntsville. Can't believe that
we're back in Huntsville. Even though
it's been four years, I stayed here in
Huntsville and lo and behold, God
convicted him or con that he needed to
come to study theology at Oakwood
University. Um, but I was no longer in
school, so I wasn't on campus.
>> So, fast forwarding
>> Yeah. that we're actually both converted
around the same time.
>> Was that your time? like me like 95 94
>> I wasn't converted then
>> and you were saying like 96
>> is when it really
>> you know in that general area so even
though you were brought up
>> Adventist
>> um and I was not Adventist at all
>> but just in those same years you know
threeyear window right
>> that we both go through a conversion
experience before we met
>> right and so God did his thing in your
life God did his thing in my life and
this is what we're trying to encourage
encourage you to do. It's like I had
he was not
looking for a wife even though he had
two children but he was not looking for
a wife. He had two children that you
know obviously um um was when he was in
the music industry but he wasn't
necessarily looking for a wife. I and
and it's funny because I relisted to a
little bit of my testimony last night
for something and it was a whole thing
but
>> um so I remembered this but I was not
I was of course wanted of course I
wanted a husband but I wasn't looking
for a husband any longer because I had
gotten out of a a bad relationship
started talking to some other people and
then not and realized ah this isn't it
it either and I said this was the prayer
I prayed I said God I don't want to date
or talk to anybody that's not the
husband Mhm.
>> And then and then when I said that, I
was really free. I was happy. I was
free. I was just it was just me and God.
And then I had my passion for the work
that I wanted to do, which was broadcast
journalism. And I was just like that I
was my life was all about that God and
me getting the job that I wanted to
have. So my my getting a husband or
dating was not on my radar at all.
>> At once I made did that prayer. Um, and
then
he came along, which was random, too,
because he was he got he just was
invited to my I'm telling the whole
story, but you were invited. You were
invited to he was invited to my home for
a potluck, a a Sabbath potluck where my
parents were in town, friends from
Oakwood were over, and a mutual friend
brought
>> um
>> brought you over. And you know, Atante
had uh like a list and on that list was,
you know, she's not going to marry a
pastor. And she
>> Oh, yeah. I forgot about that part.
>> She's not going to marry anyone with
kids.
>> No, no, no, wait. This list, I didn't
have a list. I mean, it was a list. I
guess it was a mental list. I never
wrote down a list. But I actually
told people that I graduated from Pine
Forge Academy in 1992. And I remember
telling I was 18. I told my friends
that. I said, "I will never marry a
pastor and I will never marry somebody
with children."
>> So, what love does
>> what love does
>> what love does is it changes
>> it flips your it flips your script
completely in your mind.
>> Um, and those two things were not a
hindrance to me. Mhm.
>> But I do want to say
I did take one day. I know it sounds
wild, but I took one day and it was
here. It was in Madison somewhere. I
don't know. I I don't remember the park.
I wish I could remember the park, but I
took the book Adventist Home. This is
how converted I was at the time. I took
the book Adventist Home. I took it to
the park and I prayed and I started
reading Adventist Home. Guys, you would
never think unless you've read Adventist
Home, then you already know. But
Adventist Home has one page. One page.
That book is like a little book. It has
one page. That's this much.
>> Um
about being a steparent.
And I was like, "What? That's not what I
was expecting because I was praying
about it. I was praying like, can I do
that? Can I do this? Because I like him,
but can I do that?"
>> And and this was just like I just liked
like I had heard your story. We did the
radio interview. You know, it was just
the initial things about him I liked.
>> And I was like, can I do this? And
>> and our first date was co-porting.
>> That's another thing I didn't want to
do. But then he was like, but I liked
him. And he was like, do you want to go
co-portering? He was a student
co-porter.
>> Um, and he was, and that's how he made
money to get through school and stuff.
So he was like, "Do you want to go with
me?" And I didn't. I mean, I wanted to
hang out with you, but I didn't want to
go colding. Even though I was converted,
I was like h knocking on people's doors.
That's weird, you know. Even though I
>> And she sold more books than me.
>> I sold my whole bag of books. It was so
that that's because Yeah, it was
actually it was a lot of fun.
>> It was a lot of fun. Anyways, back to
the the the steparenting book book the
part. So, that was my biggest
I don't know being a pas being married
being a pastor's wife and stepchildren
were about on the same level. Like I
sorry guys, but I had dated some
theology students prior and um that just
turned me off to that. I was like I
don't want to do that. But so I go to
the the park, I'm reading and there was
the one page in Adventist home and I
I'll never forget she uh said she wrote
and talked about how Jesus had a
stepfather. Mhm.
>> If Jesus could have a stepfather, if God
could have chose, he chose Joseph was
not his biological father. So, and if
God could choose that and, you know,
have Jesus have that, well, then I could
do that.
>> This is not the worst thing in the
world. So, it totally just changed my
perspective on what, you know, being a
steparent, you know, looks like. Still,
I'm 24 years old, so I don't fully know
what it is to to be a steparent, but
God, you know, taught me
>> along the way. So,
>> um,
the pastor thing, I remember you were I
because I remember I I was shaking,
well, I don't know. I was done shaking
your hand at that time, but I was like,
"So, what are you studying?" And you
were like, "Theology." And I was like,
"You mean like not religion? you're not
trying to just be like a an
administrator and like at a school or
something, but it was theology and you
kept saying it and I was like, "Oh my
goodness, he's studying to be a pastor.
That's not what I want." But
>> love,
>> love and God's will. Like, you don't
want you to say, "Oh, love kept me in an
abusive relationship." No, that's not
love. But God helped to change my
perspective and it was the best decision
I ever made in my life. Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> And we're talking about a love story.
>> And we're talking about a love story,
>> which is the title of the sermon today.
>> Yes.
>> Which again, it all goes together.
>> It all goes together. It all goes
together. So, let us get to your
questions. I don't know if you wanted to
add anything. I did literally did all
the talking, which is very classic for
us. But
>> yeah,
>> if he's not preaching, I do all the
talking.
>> Yeah. Well, um, you know, I will say
that,
um, I think one of the things that, uh,
a lot of people
they you can rush into a relationship
and
make mis make a mistake that will be
hard to correct. Uh, so I'm not saying
rushing.
>> I mean, you know, we were married in
under a year.
We were married within,
>> we've told this before, too, but we were
married within, not as quick as Amber
and Terry, like they just I'm teasing
you guys within 11 months.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> So, but we both knew
and
uh both knew that God was leading in
this direction.
>> Yes. And so,
um, I think
often times people can rush into a
relationship for the wrong reasons
>> or with blind spots
>> and you end up making a mistake that is,
you know, pretty costly. Mhm.
>> So, you know, as we're talking about
love, as we're talking about
relationships, and people want to know,
you know, you're either in a bad
relationship now or you're getting into
a relationship and you want to know, you
know, how do I know God's will?
>> Um, or you've gotten out of a bad
relationship.
>> Um, I think there's a lot to
um when it comes to relationships, the
wisdom of God is really, really, really
>> like needed. Like I think in the same
Adventist home, Ellen White said, "If
you're used to praying, you know, once
or twice
>> Yes. a day. Multiply those.
>> You're going to need to double double
that." Yeah.
>> When Yeah.
>> So, uh, yeah, absolutely.
>> We need to do
>> um
>> Yeah,
>> absolutely important.
>> We have a question.
>> We got a question.
>> We have a question. We're going to talk
about marriage, too. Not just for the
singles, but we have a singles question.
As a single Christian, how do I manage
my desire for sexual intimacy in a way
that honors God? I feel like uh the
church often just tells singles, "Wait
until marriage," but doesn't teach us
how to live practically with how God
made us as sexual beings. Wait until
marriage is good, but how about those of
us who may never get married?
Yeah. Wow. Great question. And yeah,
just great question. We're talking about
love. We're talking about relationships.
It's it's it's good stuff. Um,
all right. Well, first, let me say this
first because you're right to the person
who wrote this. You were absolutely
right. Um,
first of all,
Christian, and we were guilty of this
too, for sure, especially with our older
set. you know, we have two sets of kids,
our older set and our younger set
because and and uh we definitely um did
this just like everybody like a lot of
Christian families do. They don't talk
about
sex and intimacy, Christian sexual
intimacy because and and and it's
because the world puts a lot of shame
>> and you know and maybe from our past we
had shame as well. You know what I'm
saying? And so you can pass that along
to your children, to the young adults in
your church, to whoever you're you're
talking to. And I like to say that um
God was very clear like he he created
marriage
>> and he created sexual intimacy. That's
his creation.
>> Yeah.
>> So we shouldn't be so taboo about it. We
just need to of course encourage that
for just this covenant relationship.
Yeah,
>> because um that's what he built it for.
He didn't build it for
>> Yeah.
>> you to have with every single person.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Well, I was going to say that um it like
I was going to talk about this in
dating. I mean, obviously, I mean, um as
far as sexual
>> Well, let me add this before you before
you go. I want to say that
>> um you know I think that one of the
things that we in in this particular
area that we have to take into
consideration is
that
uh there are certain things that we
struggle with as a result of sin
>> right so I think had sin never entered
people wouldn't be walking around you
know lusting and wanting to like get
into a sexual relationship before
marriage
>> so that is a result of the fall. And I
think we have to take that into
consideration when we're like, man, I'm
struggling with uh desire to be with
someone. I'm not married
>> and
um you know, I want to be sexually
active.
>> We need to recognize that for what it
is, right? It is a temptation. It is um
uh it is moving outside the will of God
in which these things are are you know
strictly for the marriage covenant.
>> And so
when you understand that and you're able
to understand okay right this is the
this is the enemy trying to get me to uh
to partake of the tree of the knowledge
of good and evil.
>> Right. thinking that this is going to be
a benefit and a blessing for you when in
actuality it works against you.
>> Mhm.
>> So I think we have to understand that
that you know there is spiritual warfare
and and it's hard. It is difficult
>> right different people struggle with
different things
>> and none of those struggles are easy
struggles.
>> That's right. I want can I want to add
on to that? So, um, because I told him
we were going to be very transparent.
This is because we want to, you know,
want to be able to help. Like, I think
you should have examples. Um, you know,
when we were dating, we were, we're both
born again virgins. I like to say like
that.
>> So, we were born again. both were
committed to that's not what we both and
that was helpful that you had made your
own individual decision
>> outside of me before you met me
>> and I had made my individual decision
>> before I had met you.
>> Yeah.
>> So the commitment was to God. It didn't
matter
>> right.
>> It was just like this. Okay. But I but
we fully loved each other. We had 11
months
to be tempted with that. You know, it
wasn't like we're not going to sit up
here and say that there was no
temptation because that would be a lie.
>> Um the Bible doesn't even say that. We
you know, we know that we're all tempted
by the enemy. So,
>> but what we started to do, and this is
for the singles and for those who are
dating and not the singles, I'm sorry.
This is for those who are dating and for
the singles who will date.
>> Um but we Let's hold hands. We stopped
doing this.
we stopped doing this because this led
to other you know to wanting to
>> wanting to do other things. So um we
yeah that's what we had to do. Now I'm
just giving you an example of how God
led us. I'm not telling you that you
cannot if you're dating hold somebody's
hand or I'm not even telling you that
you cannot kiss a person. I'm just
telling you what
we had to do in our
born again um situation because we both
had experienced those things outside of
our conversion and
>> um that was well that's what kept us
safe.
>> Yeah. And being in the coming from the
world like being in the world before
meeting Christ and just living that
life. Um the devil just
tries to get you deeper,
>> you know, just so into one particular
way of thinking,
>> that and acting. So,
>> you know, out in the world, if you're a
guy, it's like, okay, um you know, the
more girls you can be with the the the
more clout you have. Mhm.
>> And so, you know, imagine going from
that to all of a sudden, all right, I'm
making a decision, right?
>> You know, um,
>> smoking marijuana,
>> right?
>> All right, I'm going to stop smoking
marijuana, you know, whatever it was
that I was doing. Okay, I'm going to
stop doing that.
>> And yeah, it's a struggle. It was a
challenge. It was a struggle. Mhm.
>> But I think going back to this question,
you know, we have to recognize good for
good and evil for evil
>> and not kind of like, oh, well, you
know, it's not that evil,
>> right?
>> Um, you don't want to give yourself when
the Bible says when two people come
together, they become one flesh.
>> Um,
and
think about the experience that you that
you
the experience that is robbed, right?
When
you give to others what
you should only be giving to your future
husband or your future wife.
>> And that
um I think every time you have a
relationship outside of the sexual
marriage,
>> you give a part of yourself away,
>> which is a kind of a crazy thing, right?
You give a part of yourself away or you
become mingled with,
you know, someone else. You end up
walking around like you're mingled with
10 people. You're mingled with 20, you
know, whatever number you God desired
the the
one man and one woman to become one
flesh,
>> right?
>> And I think a lot of people are walking
around, they're many flesh.
>> Yeah. So
consider those things and know, hey, if
I'm not married, I haven't been married
for 5 years, that's not a reason to be
like, well, the Lord's going to
understand,
>> right? So, I'm just going to, you know,
uh, go ahead and do my thing
>> and because God understands I haven't
been with anyone for I mean, I haven't
I'm not married and I haven't been
married.
>> And, you know, you pray for marriage.
>> You do pray for marriage. And I just
want to say for those who have similar
stories or experiences like us that
you've you're wanting to do the right
thing now, but you've had experiences in
the past that are not what you're trying
to do now. I mean, I just want to
encourage you that u first of all, you
need to just like I said, we were on the
same page. Yeah. you have you you don't
don't think like, oh, okay, I'm gonna
I'm gonna I'm gonna um I'm going to
follow God's will uh in this area of my
life, but I'm gonna date somebody who's
not on that same page and I'm going to
make it. No, you're not. He or she is
going to knock you off that post. You're
not that you're not going to make it.
I'm just being for real. Like, why set
you like it's just super like it's
already super hard when you are with
somebody on the right page and you guys
love each other and it's good and it's a
healthy relationship. you're going to
want to be tempted to be like, "Let me
just fully love you before you know the
time is is right." And if so, if you
start dating somebody or get with
somebody who is not on that same page
with you, it's going to be extremely
difficult. And so that's the unequally
yolked part. Like you have to be like,
if your relationship with God should be
number one, like don't cheat on your
relationship with God. Mhm.
>> I think I've never said it quite like
that, but don't have an affair on God
>> with someone that's not supposed to be
that you're not supposed to be with. If
you're with someone that you're supposed
to be with, it's you you and God
>> and that person are going to come
closer. It's like
>> God's leading them, God's leading you,
and you guys are just going to have this
wonderful relationship. Yeah.
>> Doesn't mean you won't have trials and
stuff like that. I'm not saying that.
But it's just
>> But you'll be able to get over those
trials and things that you have to do.
So
>> yeah,
>> just it don't don't make not having sex
like this big huge thing
>> in your head that like, oh my gosh, I
could never not do that if I care about
somebody. Like you have to like just
like any other thing that we overcome.
>> Seeking first the kingdom of God.
>> Seeking first the kingdom of God. Like
like he said, you said you stopped
smoking weed. Um it was like you had to
just stop doing that weed, not having
sex. I don't care what the temptation
is. I don't care what the bad vice,
alcohol, I don't care what the bad vice
is.
>> God can give you victory over that. And
and I know as a Christian, you know that
in theory, but just you need to remind
yourself to put it in its proper
perspective.
Um because sex comes with emotions.
People feel something and then they
think like, "Oh, I must respond to
that." No, you don't. It's just like
if somebody is um goodness, I'm thinking
about couples counseling, but like if
your partner is yelling at you, you
don't have to respond with that same
energy.
>> Yeah.
>> But you feel like it because when
somebody's yelling at you, you feel like
this
>> Yeah.
>> feeling of either hurtness or rage or
just fear, whatever, and you want to
respond. So you you don't have to
respond to those sexual desires because
God is walking with you. You're seeking
him first and he will carry you.
>> Yeah. Um, so yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> But the first thing is to choose
somebody that you're equally yolked with
and that loves God as much as you do and
wants to serve him as much as you do and
commit to that.
>> And someone was asking, well, what
about, you know, like this mingling of
the flesh? Uh, how do you unmingle that?
And I think the answer is very simple is
this is why Jesus said you must be born
again, right? When you're born again,
you are, as you just said, you become a
spiritual virgin,
>> right? Mhm.
>> in in in more ways than one.
>> Um you know, Revelation 14, you know,
the the remnant, the 144,000 are
literally called virgins, signifying
that they have been born again and all
the past has been washed away. So I
think that is the key thing is when you
are born again, the things of the past
are the things of the past. You have a
new page. you have a new beginning and
that's why it's called being born again.
So um
uh you know hopefully that's that will
help you know person that asked that
question as well as well as others who
struggle with that question. Um, trust
God. Trust God and
um, walk in the path of integrity and
let the Lord work out that situation.
And I think the key thing, guys, is
get yourself ready with God and I
believe God will bring the person that's
right for you,
>> right?
>> Focus on yourself.
and being the best
person in Christ that you can be,
>> you're seeking first the kingdom of God,
>> God is going to bring the the right
things into your life and the wrong
things that come that come into your
life, you'll be able to recognize it and
say, "Yeah, not for me."
>> Yes, the singleness time is for you to
get yourself just do all those good
things that you need to do so you can
show up and be the best version of
yourself in the relationship. Okay, we
must move on. I was looking at some of
these other questions and our answer,
our long winded answer to that actually
answered some of these other questions.
So, I'm going to
>> skip to something that's a little
different. How do I handle my husband
leaving me out of the blue, moving out
of the house, leaving me in debt, and
then saying he wants to work on our
marriage?
I no longer feel safe within our
marriage. Oh, okay. I mean, that's a
that's a good question. And that's you
know what you know he is saying he wants
to work on it but you're you're not
trusting you're not trusting because he
and in your you know mind left you out
of the blue. Um so um I think definitely
hopefully you're in hopefully you're in
marriage counseling. If you are not this
is something you need to be in
counseling uh for because you need to
whatever he left you for you guys need
to deal with that. I mean because you're
saying it's out of the blue. You have no
idea. he you guys need to go and talk to
a third party. I say a licensed marriage
and family therapist, somebody on that
level who can help you deal uh with
those things. Um because I don't know,
you're saying out of the blue, but it's
and I don't know the situation, but
there's
I mean anything could happen, you know.
I have no idea. So I won't I anything
can happen.
>> Sometimes you signs Yeah. You think it's
out of the blue, but it's just that
there were signs that you may have
missed.
you know um
and
because you know a person is not just
going to get up and be like hey I'm in
love today and then tomorrow yeah you
know what uh yeah I'm I'm I'm gone. So,
um, you know, whether those signs were
visible or not is, you know, um, you
know, something that you would have to
like look back and say, you know what, I
did see those signs and maybe I was
ignoring them. Maybe I didn't want to
see them or maybe you just didn't see
them at all. But it's definitely
understandable that you don't trust
because you know this individual wasn't
open with you that you know these are
the struggles I'm having. Can we work
some things out? Right? Can we you know
they didn't come to you with any kind of
discussion any kind of heads up that
that they were struggling with anything.
So it becomes difficult to trust in that
situation. Mhm.
>> Um but I don't think that it is
impossible.
Um but that is going to depend upon how
this person moves forward. How the h
that husband moves forward. Is he really
trying to uh you know because if he's
left you would just think he's like I'm
gone. But if he's left and say but
saying but I want to work things out.
Mhm.
>> You know.
>> Mhm.
>> Again, that sounds like a complex
situation.
>> Um, and it's going to require, first of
all, you have to decide, am I willing to
put in the time? Um,
>> uh, to make this work because if you're
not, and if he's not, then it's
definitely not going to work.
>> So, um,
>> yeah.
>> No, absolutely. And you're saying being
and I think and we're going to go to
this next question, but I definitely
um
you know that being unequally yolked
piece guys is so huge. It's so huge. And
I don't want to come from it from like
this legalistic way that I think it was
been used in the church pri you know in
the past. You know what I'm saying? But
>> but God is is is he he's wise. He knows
what's like the best thing and he's
like, I'm trying to make life easier for
you. Um, but if and of course if
somebody's willing to,
you know, if you guys if you guys are
willing is if you guys are willing to
get on the same page spiritually and rel
religiously and all those things and it
then it makes it so much easier. But I'm
I'm here to say that as a being married
27 years
to an amazing person. Yeah, I'm talking
about you like you're not sitting right
here to an amazing m just he's an
awesome he's a very good husband. He's
you know he's not perfect. Okay guys,
nobody's perfect but he's amazing in
many ways.
Marriage is still hard.
>> It's still hard even I don't want to
like make singles to be like oh should I
get married? Yes, you should get married
because it's still hard but it's still
as hard as it is even with an amazing
person. It's beautiful. It like there's
so much beautiful and wonderful things
that come with it. So they it kind it
balances itself out. Like if it was just
always hard, well, nobody would get
married. But but if you could always put
I mean there's going to be hard in there
because life is hard. There's things
that you go through.
>> Uh we talked about it. Dr. White and I
said it, we both said it at different
times this week, but marriage is like uh
you're on this straight road and it's
great and then you go up this huge
mountain and it's like the hardest
mountain and then you come down and you
get back on the straight road and that
could last for some years and then
you're going to hit another mountain.
But anyways, my point is saying that
it's hard to do that straight road. I
mean, it's not hard to do the straight
road, but it's hard to do the mountain
>> with somebody that is spiritually not on
the same page with you.
>> Because if I could not come to to my
husband and say, Ivor, we need to pray.
I need you to pray with me. We need
prayer. we need to, you know, this is or
we need to like spiritually look at this
problem that is going on not just
necessarily between us but like with our
children or uh just in life in general
like just everything like if we're not
on guys that is a divorce waiting to
happen. I'm sorry.
>> And as I'm now I'm speaking as a
marriage and family licensed therapist
because
>> it's so hard to go through life and you
are not on the same page like the
battles are just going to come and
you're just going to feel get beat up
every time and you need a partner with
you to be able to help you fight those
battles and those attacks. So anyways,
we're talking about love, we're talking
about marriage. To have real healthy
good love relationships, you need to be
on the spiritual same page.
>> Yeah.
So
>> if you're and if you're not there, you
know, if that wasn't the primary
uh mover behind,
you know, marriage,
you can make it the primary mover now,
>> right? So um
>> yeah,
>> if you are, no,
>> I'm definitely not telling you if you're
in that that type of marriage now. No,
no, definitely not saying that because
there was a question about that, too.
Yeah, there's always hope. There's
always hope because God is alive and
Jesus is God and Jesus are real. The
Holy Spirit is real.
>> Um, so if you're in that, I was talking
to singles right then. Those who are not
married, that's who I was speaking to
when I was doing all of that. But those
who are in a relationship like that, I
we said this I answered this question
last week for a question and answer that
definitely stay of course you need to
stay in your marriage if you don't have
biblical reasons to leave that marriage
and it's not abusive. Um, and you're
just to you're to show God and and
you're to show present God to them, not
by preaching to them, by living your
life in a godly way. You're to be that
example.
>> That's that is I don't want to say
burden, but that is what you have to do.
It's not really a burden to live for
Jesus, but
>> you have to live for Jesus in that space
>> all the time.
>> That that husband or wife needs to be
like, man, my husband is so godly in
this marriage. it makes me want to know
the Jesus. It makes me want to study the
Bible with him or if it makes me want to
study the Bible with her and pray with
her or whatever. Like you are to make
loving Jesus and having this
relationship with Jesus very attractive.
>> Yeah.
>> So, okay. And just I mean I think you
look at uh Jesus's own example
um you know God's example is that he was
in a pretty bad marriage
>> you know
>> and uh he stayed in that marriage and
tried to work it out try to work it out.
Try to work it out.
>> And the Bible says that you know you're
married until death do you part. And I
think when Jesus was put to death on the
cross, it was like, okay, so you guys
have made your decision, right? And one
of the two parties dies,
>> and in essence, the marriage is off,
>> right? Um the the New Testament bride is
different from the Old Testament bride.
But that analogy where where God is
working with humanity
>> that is imperfect
that is
uh
you know making all kinds of bad
decisions for the relationship between
them and God. Um, I think
you can see how God held out hope and
then understand
that
no matter how bad you think your
marriage is,
that
um it is possible to revive it.
>> It is possible to revive it. So, um, not
that that happens,
you know, all the time. Not that that's
100% guaranteed. Oh, it can it can be
revived, but
>> um it can be revived through
submitting to the will of God. And
that's going to take something that's
going to take both,
>> you know, parties to do that. If it's
one party that's guilty, same thing
that's guilty of ne neglect or whatever
it might be. Um but just saying that to
say that um you know there's always hope
but also understand that there are times
when it's like yeah this definitely um
is not going to work because of the
decisions of one of those one of the
parties. Mhm.
>> Yes. Okay. This does. And I mean to the
I'm going to get to this one, but
somebody asked if they need to get
married in a church or no, they said,
"Should marriages be done through the
church or is a civil court ceremony okay
in God's eyes?" Um, yeah, the civil
court makes it legal and that's I mean,
even when you get married in a church,
you're leg you're not really married. I
mean, you know, you're not really
married until the pastor signs
>> the paper. I remember one time something
happened that you didn't sign somebody's
paper
>> and they had to go back. Anyways,
>> it just has to be recognized by the
civil,
>> right? So, there's nothing wrong with
being getting married at a at a civil
court biblically. But if you um of
course want a beautiful wedding and it
could be a small, quaint, but still
beautiful wedding, that's awesome, too.
But of course,
>> putting it down on a legal paper is what
you have to do to be married
>> legally. uh legally.
>> Mhm.
>> Um Okay. I'm going to open up a can of
words, so I'm not going to go there.
Okay. So, I've been married once with
three sons by the same man, but now
divorced. I've dated since then, but my
current focus is my healing and my
relationship with God, ministry, and my
sons. In the near future, I would like
to date again, but I'm a little uh
fretful or afraid because the way the
world right now um because of the way
the world is right now and what I know
is soon um up to come upon us believers.
I'm beginning to feel that I will never
remarry again and I will have to live
the single life till Christ comes so
that I stay focused on him and his will.
But but would it be okay to still date
or hang out with a gentleman for social
uh occasion and fun even if I don't plan
to even want to marry again? Or should I
just stay out of the dating uh arena and
just focus on what I mentioned earlier
uh date myself and just enjoy girls
nights out occasionally?
They're like, I don't know. They use
that emoji. Um,
so
I
>> you want me to
>> Yeah.
>> Do you have something you have? Okay, go
ahead. I'll I
>> say that is that is not a um that is not
a you need to do this question versus
you need to do that. I think it's okay
to have to have friends. Um and you
never know, right? I mean, you are
deciding that you're you're not going to
get married again.
>> She's not saying that she's not getting
married again. She's just saying she
doesn't know if that's what
>> is in is in the plans for you. So, you
don't know. But, you know, this is one
>> Well, this is what I was going to say.
Remember, she was never going to marry a
pastor or somebody with kids.
>> That's true.
>> So,
>> so just leave that. Yeah. Only God knows
what he has for you. I do want to say
and I think we've shared this on here
before or did we share it together is
that um that never getting married it
God there's only like what there was you
could tell me if I'm wrong is there only
Jesus and and and Paul that we know for
sure that didn't get married
>> it what do you mean
>> I mean in the Bible
>> no I mean
>> I don't we don't know I mean but we
don't have examples of people not
getting married but we know Jesus and
Paul did not because they were just
doing ministry and they had their focus.
>> U and the Bible does say that it's good
for that it's it's not good for man to
be alone. So that's humanity.
>> Yeah, there were other prophets that I
mean people
>> Okay, so there's other there's other
people, but it wasn't the masses is what
I'm saying. Not the majority.
>> Um because God does say that it's not
good for man to be alone. So there are
times and we're I'm I think I said this
in mental health Monday. We're not, you
know, God knows and if it's best for
that person, but I feel that's far and
in between. That's definitely not the
majority. It's it's not if you can the
the issue or the real thing is you want
to find the right person.
>> You want to find the right person that
you can because you said you just want
to focus on God, your relationship with
God and your sons. You need to find the
right person that God has the right
person. If God has a person, it's that
person that's going to fit what you're
trying to do in life. It's going to
complement your goals in life because
those are godly goals, you know, to have
a for you to be an amazing mom for your
adult three adult sons and then um also
spend time and have a relationship with
God. So, he because that's your desire.
If he's to bring somebody into your
life, he is going to uh complement those
goals that you have or what you're
currently doing that God has called you
to do. And I would sit back and not
worry about it. Just focus on that. And
I think that's why I'm glad we let out
with our story because neither one of us
were seeking out
um a husband. I'm just like, Lord, when
you bring him, it will be evident and
we'll I'll know. And
>> yeah, I was surely wasn't seeking out a
husband.
you know what I mean? You're you're
silly. Your pastor's actually very
funny. Um he Yeah, sometimes he's not,
but sometimes he's really funny. So, um
yeah, I would just sit back and and
chill. Like, just let God do the work.
Let God bring the person. Um I know I
mean I know Amar and Terry obviously are
not on right now, but they had a similar
thing like, "Oh, there was this their
story is amazing. I love their story.
I've heard it for seven, eight years. I
could hear it more. Um, but like for
those of you who didn't know, and they
need to I think share it on Sabbath
school. I think they did way back five
years ago. They need to reshare it on
Sabbath school. They've done it for
Power Wednesday. But, you know, I'll
just tell a little snippet that and I'm
telling you to chill because like Amber
was she wanted a husband, but she didn't
know where that was coming from. And so,
God literally spoke to her. Now, you
guys see Amra's Amber's a white woman.
Obviously, you see that every week.
Spoke to her, told her to leave her
church. her church that she was doing
amazing things and told her to go across
town
and led her to a black church that she
had never been to, didn't know anybody,
and that's where Terry was.
>> I'll leave it there and let them tell
their own story. My whole point is Ammer
was chilling and then the Lord spoke and
then brought
Ivan knocked on my door. I just opened
the door and there he was. My point is,
I don't know how it's going to happen
for you to the person who wrote this,
but if God has a person for you and
wants you to be married again, he's
going to bring it about. You just chill,
focus on God, focus on your relationship
with him, and being an amazing mom to
those three uh adult sons and you're
healing from that previous marriage as
well. So,
>> yeah.
>> Well,
>> yes, I could talk about these things uh
forever. or I don't know if I'm
>> Yeah,
>> go ahead.
>> No, no, no. I I I think that's uh
>> good answer.
>> Okay. And thank you, Angela. She said
it, too. She said there's so many
examples of people who didn't get
married. So, all right. Still not the
masses, but go ahead. There, but there's
examples. I honestly believe that
a godly marriage is such a blessing.
It's such a blessing.
He's a blessing for me spiritually.
It's like he's a blessing to you guys.
Like I learned so much from him and I
think I'm a blessing to you too. He
learns from me as well. And so
>> um it's just it's
marriage is a blessing. God created
marriage just like he created all these
other things to be a blessing to us.
Just marry the right the person that God
calls for you and you will be happy.
>> You will be happy even going through and
this is what I want to hit because I
always think like when we share our
stories or they think like oh my
goodness look at them they they're just
so happy all the time. They never go
through anything. Yeah. No,
>> we go through a lot. We go through a lot
because the enemy as is always trying to
to he's he comes at all of us but he
tries to come at your marriage. You have
to fortify your marriage.
>> Yeah. you have to fortify your marriage.
>> Um I think we should do this last
question then then we can close out. But
okay
>> uh and it's kind of in line with what uh
the previous question was asking which
is in light of all the things that are
happening prophetically speaking
>> is it right to um
>> fall in love
>> to you know should we be looking to get
married? Should a person be looking to
get married
>> to the right person? Absolutely. But you
can answer your answer. Absolutely. M
>> because you can f look you you don't
want you don't want a partner like I I
want to go through the time of trouble
with you. I don't want to go through the
time of trouble by myself. Okay. So I I
would like for you to
>> to be there with me
>> honestly.
>> You know I think the I think the
question is more to is there going to be
enough time to raise a family and to and
you just don't know.
>> But maybe but maybe even though the B we
talked about this too in our worship
recently.
>> We don't we don't know. You don't know
the day or the hour, right?
>> No, you don't.
>> So, um you live live your life
and
um
allow God to take care of the future,
>> right? I want to say this, you do want
to be wise. I mean, as far as getting
married, that's a that is a beautiful
godly partnership. I think there's
there's no hesitation like, "Oh, it's
almost the time of trouble. I shouldn't
get married." To me, that just that
doesn't uh resonate. But because you if
you can have a godly Christian man or
woman with you,
>> why be alone? Like it's better.
>> I mean, to go through difficult times. I
mean, I've experienced that for 27
years. It's it's I'm happy that he can
go through these life's journey with me
instead of being alone and dealing with
it all by myself.
>> Now, the Bible
>> and she doesn't mean that we've had 27
years of a time of trouble.
>> No, we have not. But I mean, we you
know, everybody goes through difficult
times. So, but um
and the Bible, we talked about this
during a worship recently that the Bible
says, "Be fruitful and multiplied." It
never takes that back. Now, you have the
freedom of choice and say, "You know
what?
We're choosing together not to have
children because of the times we're
living in." I'm not going to tell
anybody to do that. That's your
individual choice. I think if people
were looking at things, you would be
more looking at like, do we want to have
children in the time we're in? But, you
know, in all these generations,
everybody could have said that
>> because the times the world is just
getting worse and worse, right? Like,
everybody could have said that. Um, but
the Bible's very clear to be fruitful
and multiplying, and he doesn't take it
back. So,
that has to be everyone's individual
decision. Yeah. I'm so sad that I was 30
minutes almost late because I actually
love
>> talking about love and don't want to
just talk about it when the world is
just celebrating it on one day. But
>> um yes, I for the marriages for people I
just want to close with this. The people
who are already married and you're in
this relationship, draw closer to God
and draw closer to each other. You're on
the same team, your partners. If you
needing some therapy or counseling,
definitely reach out. Even if you have a
a good marriage, but it just needs some
maintenance. All marriages can can can
do some maintenance and it's better,
reach out to a therapist or something
near you. If you're single, focus on
just you and God. Enjoy this time. I
told a single person this this morning,
I was like, "Enjoy this time." They're
not single, but they're not. They have a
boyfriend, but they're not married with
children. I'm like, "Enjoy this time
because you will be a wife and a mother
one day, and you'll never
>> That'll be what it is for the rest of
your life." So just enjoy enjoy your
singleness or enjoy your enjoy your not
not being married and not being a parent
and all of that. Enjoy this time and
then a new season in space will come and
that's also a blessing and love that
goes into it with that as well. Yeah.
>> And did I cover everybody? Married
people, single people.
>> Okay. Yeah, that's it.
>> Do you have any closing remarks? Um
I would say um
you know
seek ye first the kingdom of God.
>> That is the that is the life formula.
When you put God first he will bring the
right
uh people. He will bring the right
situations and he will give you wisdom
to discern the difference between the
right people and the wrong people. The
right situations and the wrong
situations.
>> Yeah.
>> So I think that should be our primary
thing, right? Your primary thing.
>> Seek first the kingdom of God
>> and let him bring let him create the
path that you are to walk and uh you
will have no regrets.
>> Amen. And uh Corinth Corinthians 13, the
love chapter, um follow that. So when
you meet somebody and you're just not
sure, like don't ignore red flags.
Follow that. Follow what love is.
>> And then if the red flags or what
something that that person is doing
doesn't fit in with that, that's that's
not the person.
>> Yeah.
>> Because God's going to send you somebody
who can love you according to uh his
love chapter.
No.
>> So,
>> all right. Well, we're going to talk
more about love in in the church, even
though I know it's not what we think,
but
>> it never is.
>> A love story.
>> Uh, make sure you you let people know.
Invite people. Um,
>> uh, this one's going to be good, you
guys.
>> I'm I'm always saying that.
>> I believe it.
>> Not because the word of God is good.
>> God, the word of God is good.
>> Because living mana is good.
>> Amen. living man in the church and
living mana living God's living mana and
the living man of church
>> and that's what I meant God's living man
God's living man is good is always good
so um please you guys make sure you tune
in you continue to watch and um uh you
will be blessed as we continue the
divine service
>> amen
yeah continue to watch like subscribe
and share please share invite somebody
to church uh today let them know what
they missed so that they can go back and
watch after church is over but invite
them for the divine worship service. Um,
and we want you to continue to uh
worship with us and stay tuned. But
we're going to close in prayer.
>> All right. Heavenly Father, thank you
for uh the love that you have given to
us
>> as an example of the love that we ought
to have for one another. Lord, please
bless us as we continue our worship.
Lord, I pray for everyone watching that
uh what whatever kind of relationship
they're in. um or if they are not in a
relationship right now, Lord, please
speak to them where they are
>> and help them, Lord, to to seek you
first um and add to them, Lord,
according to that. And we thank you and
pray all this in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen.
Heat. Heat.
Have you ever had that experience
standing in front of a massive
waterfall, mesmerized by its motion and
captivated by its power, drawn in by its
danger and bathed in its breathtaking
beauty? There's something about
waterfalls that arrest my attention
every time. Each one is unique and
deserves our attention and appreciation.
It's like the waters urge forward over
the edge of a cliff in eager desire to
plunge into the depths of the unknown.
Sometimes waterfalls are simply soft
trickles over a small ledge and other
times they're like roaring explosions
over cliffs. Nothing can hold them back.
The water is soft and yet because of its
persistence, it has the power to carve
canyons in the solid rock. I believe
that God created waterfalls not only to
beautify this earth, but also to
illustrate to the careful observer of
the sweetness of spiritual surrender.
You see, the water never stops to ask
what's around the next corner. It never
hesitates to take the plunge over the
edge of a cliff. It never questions its
direction.
It simply goes wherever gravity takes
it, it surrenders to the will and the
ways of gravity. And in the same way,
when we give our lives over to the
Savior, just like the waters flowing
forward in the river, we too can trust
and move forward in the ways of the
Lord, we can flow calmly along the path
that he has chosen for us. And while we
may not be able to see exactly what the
future holds, we can trust whatever is
beyond the next bend to the all knowing
compassionate creator. When cliffs of
uncertainty loom ahead in our path, we
can joyfully plunge over the edge,
pouring out our souls in unrestrained
surrender and devotion, knowing that God
has prepared for us only joy and beauty
in the unknown beyond. As the water is
surrendered to the gravity that pulls
it, so too it is only by surrendering in
complete trust to God that we will
experience this holy joy and heavenly
beauty. As the water spills over to new
territory, it leaves revival,
refreshment, and rejuvenation in its
wake. And so too, God wants to use our
experience of surrender and trust in
Jesus as a testimony reviving others who
become weary and scorched by the way.
Waterfalls can also reflect our personal
experience of losing ground or having a
fall in life. You see, it's inevitable
living in this world of sin that at
times we'll face the hardship of
bankruptcy, sickness, divorce, disease,
and even death. Many times we feel like
these falls are the end of our lives.
However, just as the waterfall is not
the end of the stream, so too our losses
are not the end of the journey. Rather,
we must learn to see our losses as new
beginnings, fresh ground where we can
find new life, new territory for us to
grow in the streams of righteousness in
this dry and wicked world.
But even in the waterfall, we can say
like Paul did, I count all things but
loss for the excellency of the knowledge
of Christ Jesus my Lord, for whom I have
suffered the loss of all things and do
count them but rubbish that I may win
Christ. So remember, the waterfall is
not the end. It's a new beginning. It's
simply the next phase in the stream of
life. And as you keep moving forward in
full surrender, you will find calmness
and peace just around the bed.
Ultimately, let us remember and never
forget that Christ is the great
waterfall of life. He came from heaven
to earth to give us new life. A never
failing stream of love that flowed from
the throne of God into the hearts of
men. His fall was our refreshment. His
death was our life. And today he
promises you, I will pour water upon him
who is thirsty and floods upon the dry
ground. I'll pour my spirit on your
descendants and my blessing on your
offspring. and you will spring up like
the grass, like flowers by flowing
streams. And so today, if you feel dry,
dusty, dirty, or spiritually dead, come
to the living water. Let it fall upon
your life in showers of heavenly
blessing to revive, refresh, and
rejuvenate you as well as those around
you as you continue to flow forward in
the streams of spiritual life.
We hope you've been blessed and inspired
by this new Reflections of Hope episode.
This episode is one of many that's been
produced all over the world. If you
haven't done so yet, please give our
video a like, share it with your
friends, and please follow us on
Instagram, Facebook, and YouTube. If
you'd like to see more inspiring
episodes and get access to much more
uplifting content, please go now to
patreon.com/revelationof
hope and sign up to be a member of our
Patreon page. Your monthly support will
not only give you early access to many
more inspiring videos, but it will also
enable us to continue to produce more of
these cinematic object lessons from
nature. Our goal is to produce and
release these episodes much more
frequently. So please prayerfully
consider partnering with us so that we
may continue to share the hope of Jesus
all over the world. Thank you so much
for your support. Aloha and Marin
Heat. Heat.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
So good to see that you stayed with us.
And some of you are just joining us for
the first time today. Please share,
invite other people to church today and
to worship with you. Make sure you like
and like and share uh the YouTube
channel that you are viewing um on my
living mana, our YouTube uh YouTube uh
living mana channel, church channel.
Please like and share that channel with
uh someone. Put it on your social media.
Invite someone to church to worship with
you. So happy that you guys are still
here with us. Please, if you did not
tell us where you were viewing from um
during our first uh service. Please tell
us now if this is your first time,
please put a one in the chat. We want to
say a very special welcome to you. And
just to tell you a little bit more about
Living Mana Church. I don't know about
you guys, but I had a lot of fun. And
probably you could tell I was doing most
of the talking, which you know, he
usually does most of the talking once we
start this the the uh Sabbath school
study time. But I had a lot of fun
during uh that uh during our Sabbath
school time today because we were
talking about love, biblical, godly love
uh from the Bible and what God wants for
each and every one of us. He wants us to
experience love because he loves us so
much. He wants the very best things for
us. And so, um, definitely if you didn't
catch it, go back and watch it after the
divine worship is over. Want to welcome
I don't know the first name, but it's
from Leach, Texas. Welcome. Good to see
you here. Always good to see you here,
Barbara from Anguila. Uh, loved I think
it was last week when you shared about
your prayer team and the amazing things
that they do. That was great. But we're
happy to have you here with us. Uh, we
have uh it looks like Ricardo from Reno,
Nevada. Welcome. Good to see you here.
Good to see you here. Um I'm not sure
the name, but from Montgomery, Alabama.
Good to see you here uh at Living Mana
Church. And again, if this is your first
time, just put a one in the chat and let
us know that you're visiting with us for
the very first time. Want to uh welcome
Darnell from Trinidad and Tobago. Good
to see you here uh with us, Darnell. It
is so good to have all of you here and
from so many different locations today.
Well, we do have some out of the country
and some here um in in the United
States. We last week we had so many
international from different parts of of
the world that I don't think we've ever
had before. And so it's just such a
blessing to see that and how Living Mana
Church is growing. So you can continue
to put in the chat where you're viewing
from and we will continue to say welcome
to you. We have another Trinidad in
Tobago. Ayana, she's always uh with us.
One of our um leaders um in the prayer
on the prayer team. She helps with that.
Um and she's just a blessing to hear
have here at Living Mana Church. Want to
remind you guys how we can stay how you
and how we can stay connected to you. Um
one of those ways is by getting text
alerts. And these text alerts will
remind you of when programming what is
coming usually 20 minutes before the
programming starts here at Living Manage
Church. It also like uh last yesterday
evening and this morning you guys were
sent texts to say, "Hey, we're talking
about love and we'd like your questions
and you guys were able to send in your
questions." And so when you stay
connected to Living Out of Church in
that way, that's how you're able to get
this information. So, I want to show you
guys how you can be able to do that. And
we still have more people signing in or
saying where they're from. So, we have
England, welcome. U more in Texas,
welcome. Jamaica, always welcome to all
of you. So, this is how you can stay
connected to Living Mana Church and get
the information that's needed all
throughout the week or whenever we're
sending out information. You can text
LMOC to that 855 number that you see on
the screen. And when you sign up, you
will or when you do that, it
automatically signs you up and you'll be
able to get information um get
reminders, all the things that we need
to communicate to you and that helps us
to stay connected to you. Um you can
also scan the QR code. Now, this only
works if you're in America. If you are
not in America, you're going to want to
sign up for Mighty Networks, but even if
you are in America, you still want to
sign up for Mighty Networks. And the
link in to do that is in the chat. So,
uh, please click on that link so you can
sign up for Mighty Networks, but in
Mighty Networks, this is our virtual
church home. It's our church hub, if you
will. This is where, uh, you'll be able
to message people within the church.
This is not just church members, but
viewing audience. You can sign up as
well. You can find out about our small
groups there on Mighty Networks.
And again, this is how you're going to
be able to stay connected and get
messages. Uh like we were talking with
sister an at the beginning of our
Sabbath school time. She said, "ER reach
out to me on mighty networks if you're
wanting to get a computer." That's where
you'll be able to find her and many
others. Our afterlow after today's
worship service, the afterlow where you
can all join and go over what you
learned in Sabbath school about what
um really spoke to you or spoke to your
heart in the message. just all of these
things uh you'll be able to discuss and
pastor Myers and myself uh we are on
there as well. So you guys come together
and um it's a lot of fun to be on mighty
networks and to become get closer
together form a community here at Living
Mana Church. Also want to remind you
guys about LMOC Kids. We do have
children's programming and LOC kids
starts at 11:30 central time and you can
get more information and sign your kid
up uh or kids plural uh at that you just
have to text kids to that 855 number and
so you will be able to get all the
information. If you're out of the
country you can email um the leadership
team there at LMLC kids at living.urch
and I can tell you that the LOC kids
they have a lot of fun they are
learning. They're not just having fun,
but they're having fun learning the
biblical things um of God's word in a
very exciting way. So, it's a very good
program that they put on for our
children. So, get if you want more
information, email them or text kids to
that 855 number. also want to let you
know that you can re you can um speak to
Pastor Myers if you're needing to and
you can set up a virtual
uh appointment so that you can have a
virtual office appointment with him
because he does have virtual office
hours. So if you need to do that, please
send an email to Patrice at living.live.
Also wanted to talk to you guys about uh
men's ministry. We do have that and
we're calling all men to uh join and and
it's completely it's it's a wonderful
setting. Not that I've ever been because
I'm not a man, but from what I hear from
the men and that is that it's an amazing
time, an amazing bond. They the men's
ministry, they're so close. Uh they
they're so close. You can just see the
the bond that they have formed. And so
if you're wanting more information and
to be a part of that or if you know um
um a a man in your life that you think
would benefit from it, definitely share
this information with him and he can
text men to that 855
number or reach out to the um on mighty
networks because if you're out of the
country that won't work for you, but on
mighty networks reach out to the men's
ministry. Um they have an area on mighty
networks. You can reach out to them and
say, "Hey, I want more information. and
I'd like to to get started in coming to
the men's ministry, you can do that on
Mighty Networks as well. And so we don't
just have men's ministry, we also have
women's ministry. Um and so you can
uh reach out to them as well. It's great
time to have fellowship with uh the
women um in our church and um even our
viewing audience. It's a great time. And
I want you to say and I want to tell you
that the men's and ministry uh men's and
women's ministries are all confidential
safe spaces that you can just come and
share Bible study but real women's
issues, real men's issues. You could
that's just a wonderful time to get
together with um like believers um that
are going through the same things uh
that you are or just coming and just
supporting each other as you're going
through this life's journey. So all the
information is there on how you can get
involved in the women's ministry and
there's the QR code as well. And I just
want to let you know that uh mental
health Monday we are continuing our
discussion. This is we've done three a
three-part series so far on men's
ministry. So I think that's a good
segue. I was just talking about men's
and women's ministry. But we have been
talking about men's ministry. I'm sorry
not men's ministry but men's mental
health issues. And I love it because a
lot of men are showing up, but a lot of
women are showing up, too, because
they're learning how to support the men
in their life with um just their
emotional issues. Just I I tell it to
Dr. White all the time. I feel like men
have been um not purposely ignored, but
society has ignored their mental health
issues in the sense that you would just
tell men to be strong and just deal with
it or not feel comfortable to show their
emotions. And so we're talking about all
of those things that men deal with. And
so this Monday is going to be some of
the same. We're going to continue um to
discuss the issues that men go through.
Also want to remind you guys about True
Health Tuesday that with Dr. Maria Jose
Humel. She is doing some amazing stuff,
guys. I know I say this all the time. I
say it all the time, but you're if
you're not if you're not able to watch
it live at 8:00 PM Central time, go back
and watch it when you can because you're
missing some vital good nutritional
information. These are things that these
are decisions that you can make. You
don't have to go to a doctor to eat
healthy or do different things that
she's talking about. I mean, you can
definitely talk to your medical doctor
if you have any concerns, but these are
things that you can do uh on your own
and you're already uh eating, right? So,
just change, you just need to change a
few thing. I don't know. You just have
to depends on your situation and what
you you she's sharing, but this is
accessible to everyone. So, you don't
want to miss True Health Tuesdays and
that's Tuesday at 8:00 p.m. Central
Standard Time. Also want to let you guys
know that uh the Manic Connect
newsletter, we talked about that last
week with Sister Denise. Uh family, just
check um a reminder, the second edition
of the Manic Connect newsletter is
officially out. And let me tell you, the
men are showing up and showing out in
this one. Be sure to check out the
powerful articles and the inspiring
interviews featured this month. You can
find the link in the chat and mighty
networks or text to receive it directly.
Stay connected, stay informed, and stay
encouraged. Mana connect continues to
spotlight the incredible things
happening across Living Mana. So, that's
exciting. It's so good um to hear about
that. So, definitely check that out so
you can read those stories. Also want to
remind you that give mana is our space
on mighty networks dedicated to both
outreach and outreach ministry. It is
designed to make connecting with
resources simple and meaningful. Whether
you're seeking help, offering support,
or guiding someone to the right place in
their local community.
So that's something just to remind you
about what li what give Mana does. And
if you're wanting more uh information,
you can email that email on your screen
or you can text Mana to that 855
number. Also want to remind you guys
about the LMLC business directory. Um
from Abraham's honorable dealings uh to
the early church's radical generosity,
scripture affirms the power of believers
supporting one another in commerce. Um,
as the remnant church, we continue this
legacy, strengthening the body of Christ
by hiring um, investing in and uplifting
the vocations of fellow believers. The
living mana business resource directory
is now available on the mighty networks
plat, the platform under give mana. Give
mana. Church members and friends who own
a business are invited to submit their
listings by emailing that email that you
see there on your screen with your full
name, business name, and a phone number.
So, that sounds really uh exciting. All
right. So, you guys can you guys can
definitely connect um in that way by
sending an email if you're wanting your
business to be in the business
directory. All right. Um, we just want
you guys to tell you a little bit more
about Living Mana Global. Most of you
are familiar that we do, um, translate
in seven different languages. And if
you're wanting to support that or know
more about that, I will tell you at the
end of this clip. But again, just want
to give you uh, an idea of what that
looks like so you can know what you are
actually supporting.
for
what
support uh Living Mana Global. Uh you'll
be able to do that. Um and you can go to
adventistgiving.org.
This is where you can give your tithe
and your offering. So when you go on
adventistgiving.org,
you click in the righth hand corner, you
put in living mana church and a virtual
tithe envelope drops down and you are
able to give your tithe which helps to
support the Northeastern Conference and
the worldwide 7th Day Adventist Church.
when you give to the local church budget
that stays here with Living Mana Church
and it helps us to do all the things
that Living Mana Church does uh so that
we're able to uh have all of the
equipment the the the good equipment
that we can have to be able to broadcast
live and in good quality. It helps us to
be able to uh when you give to the
benevolence fund help those who are in
need. So when they reach out and asking
for help from Living Matt Church, we're
able to pull it from that fund and all
the other things that help us to go
around the world with the gospel and
good quality um on YouTube and just on
social media. So when you're giving to
Living Mana Church, it is um again going
to all the things that Living Mana
Church is doing all around the world to
help and to support those things when
you give to the local church budget. If
you are not wanting to give virtually,
you can mail in your tithe and offering.
And there's the address on the screen.
And that's PO Box 428 Owens Crossroads,
Alabama 35763.
when you want when you mail it in, we
need you to uh just write on a little
just also slip a little note in there
saying how much is for offering, how
much is for tithe, or what if you're
wanting to support the benevolence fund
or even Living Mana Global or something
else that you want to support. Um that's
with Living Mana Church. And so those
are the two ways that you can give. We
are also, we don't have it up today, but
we will have a QR code because our
living man of church also has a zel. So,
if you have zel and you would like to
There, there we go. There it is. All
right. you can scan uh that QR code and
that will um go directly to Living Mana
Church because we are signed up with Zel
to make your giving easier for you if
that's another way that you would like
to give outside virtually outside of
Adventist giving. So, those are the
three ways that you can give uh to
Living Mana Church. We're so thankful
for all of you, for all that you do, for
your prayers, uh, for your support, uh,
financially, but just physically being
here, for your prayers, and just your
kind words. You you you guys are some
beautiful people who are our me in our
membership and our viewing audience.
Like, you choose to be here. here. And I
know people choose to be in a brick and
mortar, but for you to be here online
and in worship with us, you're really
saying, "I love what Living Mana is, how
God is leading them, what they're all
about, and I want to fellowship with
them." And you're making that choice,
and we're very thankful. And you share,
and you tell other people about Living
Man Church, and that's what it is all
about. We want to continue to go into
all the world and to share the gospel of
Jesus with the whole world. Um, and we
love that people are able we love being
in this space online because people can
just stumble upon us and it's it's just
a beautiful thing. Um, and then we can
intentionally invite and bring people.
So, it's coming from all different uh
directions. But we're just thankful for
what God has done. And again, we're
almost four years old. On April 9th,
that is what we will be. And so we are
uh just looking forward to celebrating
another year of existing as a um a as a
real church here within the 7th Day
Adventist um family of churches. And so
we're just so thankful that Living
Matter Church has made it thus far and
we are praying that it will continue to
grow and to get better and we can all do
that together as God leads us um and how
we should move forward. So, I just want
to thank you, thank God, and just want
to whisper a prayer to God right now
just of thanksgiving. So, if you please
bow your heads with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, I thank you for
the Sabbath. I thank you uh just for the
Holy Spirit who Lord, you know, when
we're hurting and when we're overwhelmed
and the Holy Spirit just can come in and
calm us and just speak to us and just
touch us and help us to feel better.
Lord, there's always things like that
going on in all of our lives. And we
just thank you for your goodness and
your grace. Lord, I thank you for every
viewer right now. Lord, I want to lift
up what's on their heart. Lord, you know
what's on their heart. I don't know
what's on their heart, but that thing or
those things. I'm asking, Lord, for
them. I'm interceding for them to you,
God, that you will answer those prayers
on their heart, Lord. There's so many
different categories. I go through them
every week, Lord. but you know exactly
where that prayer request is coming
from. So Lord, please work a miracle in
their situation. Comfort them. Help them
to know that you are with them. Lord, I
pray for Pastor Meyers and the sermon
that you have given to him a love story.
He said it was going to be very um that
it was going to be fire and it was going
to just bless our hearts. And we believe
that because you gave him the message
and your Holy Spirit is the one that um
makes things special and deep and
resonate in our hearts and helps to
change us. Lord, I believe that that's
what it's going to be because of you. So
Lord, we just ask that the Holy Spirit
would use him as he delivers that
message to us and we will respond
according to your will the way you want
us to respond. And I ask all these
things in Jesus name. Amen.
Scene 5A, take one
to cuddle up there.
>> Hey, right back.
>> Not that.
>> What is love? That's a That's a deep
question.
>> You want to answer that?
>> The little things.
>> Yeah.
>> Is what really shows what love is.
>> We're still on our honeymoon.
>> We tell everyone we're still on our
honeymoon.
>> Really? Nobody told us when it was
supposed to be over, so we just
continued.
>> Still on our honeymoon. It'll be 49 in
August. Yeah,
>> it wasn't love at first sight.
>> Well, maybe for for one of us, it maybe
love at first sight. At least at least
at least I thought, wo, she's really
pretty.
>> Maybe like 10th sight, but
>> somewhere in there.
>> Oh, okay.
>> You said I love you first.
>> I did.
>> I actually laughed at him. I had to
apologize later. Love is waiting until I
make sure I haven't injured myself when
I've tripped and fallen before she
starts laughing.
>> And it's sometimes very hard to do that.
>> Love has been rooted in my faith because
Jesus had the ultimate sacrifice of
love. There is no greater love.
>> We've learned together. We read the
Bible together. We grow together.
>> God knew what he was doing long before
we did. And that unconditional love when
he's doing it for us, how can we not do
it for each other?
>> We can actually share Christ's love with
other people through our marriage and
demonstrate how Christ actually loves
us.
>> Every night before we go to bed, we pray
together. It's really, really difficult
to be mad at each other too at the end
of the day if you're praying together.
>> Love is patient. Like the first part of
that verse is really stood out to me
because it really is about like humbling
yourselves and being patient with that
person. Jesus's example of love helps me
in the times that I don't feel like
showing love.
>> Yeah. Going back to being love is
patient, love is kind, and just taking
that ultimate sacrifice of Jesus loving
us and and and showing that to one
another. That's that's really love.
How deep the father's love
for us.
How vast beyond all me
that he would give his only son
to make a rich his treasure.
How great the pain of serial
loss.
The father turns
his face away
and the wounds and more. that you're the
one.
Bring many
sons to glor.
Behold
the man upon the cross.
My sin upon his shoulders.
ashamed. I hear my mocking
voice
call out among the scalers.
It was my sin that held him there
until
it was a compliment.
His dying breath has brought me to life.
I know that it is feed.
My will, my boast.
>> No gift, no power, no wisdom,
>> but I will boast in Jesus
Christ.
is a death and resurrection.
Why should I gain from his reward?
I cannot give an
answer,
but this I know with all my heart.
His wound has paid my ransom.
Why should I gain from his reward?
I cannot
give an answer,
but this I know with all my heart.
His wound has paid my rent.
Here
at Living Mana, we bear each other's
burdens. When you need support or
prayer, when you're feeling discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
Hey, Amen. Amen. Greetings, saints of
the most high God. Visitors and friends.
Welcome to another edition of Living
Manners Prayer and Praise Time. I'm
Brother Terry here with my lovely bride
Amra, love of my life. And we want to
welcome y'all to uh Hey, it's love day,
right? I mean,
>> it is love day. Well, it's love day
every day. But
>> yeah, but you know, we've been talking
about love today here in a special way
because look, the world's talking about
love, right? And you know the world's
symbol of love. Look, I got something
here.
>> He's got a prop.
>> Okay. So, when you when you Yes. When
the world when the world thinks about
love, right? What are they? This is what
comes to mind. Either it's a Valentine
or it's chocolates or sweets or some
romantic outing, uh Valentine's Day
cards, nice pretty stuffed animals, all
of which she had to have, right? But you
know what? We want to give you a special
Valentine's Day from God. Here is the
symbol right here.
This is a symbol of the love of God
right here. This is the greatest love
symbol the world has ever known right
here. And it represents the greatest
love story ever told. In fact, that love
story is still being written right now.
And God's writing it in your life. And
so, we want to share with you today just
briefly a special Valentine from the
Lord. You know, first lady mentioned the
men's group and uh this the men's group
are now going through steps to Christ
and this past Tuesday uh we were reading
from chapter 3 and chapter 3 just
happens to be on repentance.
You know repentance is
actually a part of the everlasting
gospel. We know that right? And the
everlasting gospel is what? What's the
gospel?
>> The love of Jesus.
>> It's good news. It's good news.
>> It's good news, right? So when we hear
about repentance, repentance is actually
good news. You know, usually we hear
about repentance, we're thinking, "Oh
yeah,
>> that's going to be a rough message to
hear, right?" But actually, it's the
perspective we have that makes the
difference. Repentance is God's
Valentine saying,
>> "I want you. Be my Valentine. Turn from
that and come to me." Now, that's good
news, right? In spite of what you've
been through, in spite of who you are,
in spite of what you've done, God's
Valentine to us is repent. In other
words, come to me. I'll receive you.
>> As you are.
>> As you are. Right.
>> As you are. You don't have to be
perfect. You don't have to have it all
together.
>> Come to me. Yes.
>> And then he will do the rest. And so
that's good news, right?
>> That's great news.
>> Look, I know. Look, I know the the
chocolate tastes good, right? the
romantic denders, the desserts and all
that. But you know what the psalmist
said? He says, "Oh, taste and see that
the Lord is good. Come and taste of the
love of God. I tell you saints, it is
sweet, sweeter than honey." We're
talking Pastor and Tante were talking
about their love story today and and me
and Amra and uh this is the reward. I
believe pastor was right right on the
money when he said, "You know what? You
just get ready and get yourself ready
and you walk with him and fall in love
with him. He will bless you beyond what
you can imagine or think. You know, I
know Amar never imagined that her the
love of her life would be coming from
where I came from, right? And I
certainly didn't expect to be where I
was and sit up and see her there. But
God is able to do exceeding abundantly.
>> He's my forever prison boo.
>> Yeah. No, but um
I like to refer to myself as a postc
crime achiever. Yes. Right. Thanks to
Jesus.
>> Crime achiever.
>> Jesus has done it.
All right. So, anyway, praise the Lord.
Before we get into praise report,
special shout out to our beautiful
friend Jessica, our sister Jessica. She
is here today watching. Jessica, love
you. And
>> please, everyone, welcome Jessica Egan.
It is her very first time.
>> Yes, Jessica, welcome to our beautiful
Living Mana family. We are honored,
honored to have you. And I believe our
friend Mary from Alabama is watching.
Um, I'm pretty sure she is. Mary, if
you're watching, hey, uh, listen, we
love and appreciate you and I I think
you'll find that you'll fit in perfectly
right here at Living Mana. And so,
everyone, just welcome Mary. I don't I'm
not sure if she's watching or not. And
also my young friend from work, Justin
Behenna, if you're watching, love you,
brother. And, uh, welcome to Living
Mana. Also, we want to welcome Brother
Jason Diggs, who is our newest member of
Living Mana Church.
>> Welcome to the family.
>> Welcome, brother Jason. Yes. Yes. Yes.
And now listen, before we get into
uh u the praise reports, these love
stories. God's got a love story for you,
saints. So share your praise reports.
You can share about your love story, how
the Lord just loved on you and brought
you through, heard and answered your
prayers. We're looking forward to it. We
love sharing the praise reports because
they encourage us and lift us up. But I
want to shout out a special family. And
I mean this family got tried in
beautiful Trinidad in Tobago right there
in the in Rio Claro in the Nariva Mayaro
Province. The Stevens family. I hope you
all are watching because I want to shout
you all out in there with our beloved
sister Joanne Coach. She got a house
full today and more coming. But Sean, if
you're watching, much love to you.
Clint, Anisha, Brena, Roxan, Tyrell,
Shawn II, if you're there. Also, Aunt
Aunt Aunt Py if you're watching, Naen,
Bella, Barry, and Ricardo. Wow, you talk
about tribe. They got that. Listen,
nothing like family love. Y'all stay
together, pray together, worship
together today. We love y'all, and we
just wanted to send a special shout out
to you. And so, yes,
>> and thank you everyone in the chat. We
wish we had time to go through and
personally call you out. Um, but we
don't have time today for a full roll
call. So, thank you so much for all of
your
>> You want to start one? I mean, you don't
know. I'm
>> We'll be here a while.
>> Hey, Sister Nicole, love you. All right.
Shout out to some of the brothers. Elder
Robert E. Plant, love you, my man.
Clint, love you. John, love you,
brother. Oh my gosh. Elco Ross, all the
men. I got to get them in some
>> Oh, you know what? Today is Chalala's
birthday.
>> Chala, happy birthday. Birthday to you.
Happy birthday to you. Shala is from the
Fab 7.
>> And the Fab 7 are going to be leading us
in ancestry prayer today. But Shala,
wow. Thank you for reminding me of that.
It's your birthday and we love you. She
is a living man a war yet. And really a
prayer warrior, man. I was I get on with
the with the Fab 7. I can these
Christine Marisella, Sister Barbara,
Sister Tammy. I mean, real prayer
warriors there. And uh love y'all. Love
y'all so much. Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Um who else can I wish we
Jodie? Sister Jodie. Love you, Sister
Jod. Beautiful Sister Jod heading up our
El Moses program with all of our
beautiful students there. Love y'all.
Love y'all. Who else?
Pauline, I see you. Sister Pauline's in
the chat. Love you, my big sister. Amen.
Always encouraging me every day. So
anyway, the chat's running kind of slow
on my side.
>> No, it's not. And Ayana, he can't help
do roll call. He can't help.
>> Ayana,
>> he can't.
>> Love you, my sister. My beautiful sister
is also in Trinidad and Tobago.
>> Is in your blood.
>> Yes, it is.
>> All right. There's a reason for that.
You know, when you got family like this
and you got tribe, you just don't want
to leave anybody out. One more time,
Jessica. So glad you could be here with
us. You are a blessing to us. We love
you. We love you. Love you. Okay.
>> All right.
Before I share praise reports, just a
reminder, if you have a prayer request
or a praise report that you would like
to submit, um
or if you would like to join the prayer
team family, we are always looking for
new people to join us. We have lots of
people to pray over. Please send an
email to pray livingmana.urch.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> And we would love to. You don't have to
be a member of living mana to serve on
the prayer team or in ministries in
general. You just need to be a member if
you're on leadership. So if you're
interested in joining us, please send an
email.
>> Yeah. If you are requesting a special
ops team for yourself or a loved one,
and for those who don't know what a
special ops prayer team is, it's more
detailed prayer that happens um daily
with small groups of people. Please send
an email to spec ops at living.urch.
If you are looking for a midweek pickme
up, please join us on Wednesdays for
power Wednesday. It's either a
devotional or a testimony and then we
break we have small uh short prayers
over the course of that. Um and it's
just an amazing time to connect and to
pray for each other and over our church.
Um following that is the power line and
that is live prayer that happens on
YouTube. Um so join us for the power
line um right after power Wednesday.
>> Amen.
>> So that is this week's announcements.
Pretty short this week.
>> Thank you my love.
>> You are welcome. All right. First prayer
praise report coming from Stacy. I
prayed with a neighbor several times
before Thanksgiving for her daughter who
had stage four cancer. I ran into her
earlier this week and she said her
daughter is in remission. Praise the
Lord.
>> Yes.
>> That's amazing.
>> Yes, it is.
>> From Jamie. Praise God for every
heartbeat and every breath. He held my
104year-old
grandmother through a procedure this
week.
>> Praise God.
>> Wow.
>> Amen. That is that's that's
>> much love to you sister Jamie there in
Compton. Give your love to our mother to
your mother
>> to her grandmother 104.
>> We are Yes. But her mother too. Her
mother who's been hearing us pray
>> all generations.
>> From our own Joanne Steven. I praise and
thank God for bringing me through back
surgery, for healing me, and for those
who prayed for me, especially on the
night I was scared, spitless when I
accidentally pulled out the tube from
the drainage sack in the surgical site.
>> I am still a bit sore and weak, but I am
recovering beautifully. Thank you,
Locoscris, for your fervent prayers. I
love you and appreciate you.
>> Love you, too, sir.
>> Amen. And you know,
on the evening of Joannne's back
surgery, she was still sending messages
and
in Power Wednesday,
>> I believe that was Yeah,
>> Joanne is a true soldier.
>> Yes, she is. We are blessed to have her
>> from Olive. I went to see my doctor
yesterday. Labs were drawn and I read
the results in their clinical portal. My
doctor hasn't called me yet, but I
already know that I will need my
infusion as my inflammatory markers are
grossly abnormal. I praise God that we
caught it at an early stage before it
got worse. My medications were all
refilled and it is given how it can mask
the symptoms, but I slept well last
night and was relieved by the pain,
tingling sensation, and tightness in
both of my hands. Amen. Yes, it is an
autoimmune disease flare up. I had been
very strict with my diet, but I can tell
you honestly that even if I stayed on
it, there were times when I got
comfortable. I sort of laid back for at
least a year and with my medical
follow-ups. My bad. There's no one to
blame but me. But now it is reset time,
not only physically, but spiritually for
me. God made me realize and recognize it
over the last few days. My closest
analogy is sinning. God hates sin and we
continue to sin. It does not please him.
So I see what is obvious here. I need to
get back to God's original plan when it
pertains to my body, the temple of the
Holy Spirit. And yes, I had been through
some personal changes which which
stressed me affected my immune system as
well.
>> I am immuno compromised to start with
and there's nothing I can do about it
without his divine interventions. Praise
report. I thank God for redirecting me
and the godly wisdom moving forward. I
will be back to how God restored my
health four years ago. I have the past
year to make up for it. And please pray
for me to have my absolute resolve on
this matter and to be uprooted in Christ
and resilient in life. Thank you for
your continued prayers. Love to you all.
God be with me on this journey. Amen.
And amen.
>> Amen.
>> This is both a request for continued
prayer and praise for God's leading.
>> Amen. Sister Olive is a sweetheart. You
know, love you, Sister Olive. Thank you
for sharing, too. Absolutely. From
Sharon Fay Johnson.
>> Amen.
>> Praise God. Thank you, Lord Jesus, and
the blessed Holy Ghost. My
daughter-in-law stated, "My son George
is in recovery. The doctor said
everything went well and they will keep
him in the hospital for wound care.
They're going to show her how to care
for the wound and it may take him a
couple of months to completely heal.
Thank you all so very much for your
continued prayers. love and support.
Now,
>> Amen. Amen. Amen.
>> When I read this praise report about
wound care, it just reminded me of my
friend Jessica, who happens to be on
Living Mana Live for the very first
time.
>> Amen.
>> And I just wanted to share something.
So,
Jessica was in a horrible car accident.
Um I believe it was two days before
Christmas.
the week of Christmas and her car was
completely totaled. She had to be
removed by the Jaws of Life. Um, she had
a compound fracture in her leg. Her her
ankle was shattered, her lower leg
shattered, her toes on the other foot
fractured, her wrist fractured. And her
friend recently asked her, who is not a
believer, where was God? Why did he
allow this car accident to happen? Now,
she showed me pictures of what her car
looked like and we happened to have the
same vehicle
>> and
God was with her and spared her life.
Absolutely.
>> She would not be alive today if it
wasn't for the Lord. And not only that,
>> she had a friend's uh she got out of the
hospital and she couldn't stay in her
own home. Um because she's she can't
walk. She's wheeled. She can walk a
little bit on a walker to the bathroom
next door 8 ft away, but she can't
really walk, right? So her friend and
her husband took her in into the guest
room that has a bathroom that she can
use and she's had friends come and help
take care of her. And so God has shown
up through her whole journey.
>> Yeah. and I I just look forward to a
testimony um of his complete healing.
So, please keep her in prayer. She has a
metal halo on her leg with rods keeping
the bones together and hopefully in a
few months she'll be able to have that
removed and get plates and screws put in
so that she can um walk freely again.
But um
>> she's awesome. So Jessica Eeken,
>> amen.
>> Much love for you. Thank you for showing
up to church today for the first time.
And we are praying for a complete
healing very soon.
>> Definitely. And for everyone else. Uh
thank you all for welcoming our friend
and our sister Jessica. We love her. And
uh and listen, you know, um we the word
of God still says what it says 1
Corinthians chapter 10:13 that God with
these temptations we're facing, he will
with the temptation also make a way of
escape. Sometimes we're just looking for
the end result, but you know, when we
look back on these amazing love stories
that God is writing in our lives and
through our lives, we will see that it's
not just the end where we see the
romance. It's not just at the end where
we see the love. It's through the
process. He's there all along. And so be
encouraged. Somebody right there in the
middle of your storm. Christy, I was
talking to my mom about you yesterday.
Christy from South Carolina. Love you,
my sister. Brother Philip Bautista, I
see you there, man. We're blessed to
have you here at Living Mana, man. What
an amazing brother you are. And brother
Reed, I saw your comment in the chat.
Love you, my man. Listen, I'm inspired
by you. Iron sharpens iron. Men of God,
we will uh pull together, encourage one
another, and be strong in the Lord. I
want to say you know the perspective on
repentance once again everybody God has
a valentine for each and every one of us
and it doesn't always come the way we
think repentance we all here comes the
fire right repentance is God saying
simply be my Valentine
>> I still want you
>> would you be mine that's what repentance
is what a perspective about repentance
he's saying come to me that's good news
that's good news somebody all right well
it's time to go to the throne of grace
And we are blessed today once again to
have um the Fab 7 who is Papa Ronnie's
um special ops prayer team. I believe
sister Barbara will be here with us
again today and sister Tammy. And get
ready for some true intercessory prayer.
Bless you as you come today, sisters.
Amen. Amen.
So I know sister Barbara there she is
and sister Tiana there you are.
>> Hello ladies. Thank you for joining us
>> from Jamaica.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> Yes
from the beautiful.
>> I will start by saying happy
>> happy from Anguila. Happy Sabbath,
church family, especially Brother Diggs,
our new church member. And happy Sabbath
to future church family members.
And happy Sabbath to our visitors,
especially Jessica. We're so happy to
have you with us today.
And yes, Sister Atante, the Fab Seven
are back again. And we're going to be
with you the whole month of February.
What a blessing. We are Papa Ronnie's
special ops team and Papa Ronnie is
pastor's father who is in a long-term
care facility for various issues.
And we are so blessed to be able to pray
for Papa Ronnie.
But I have to tell you about our name,
the Fab 7. We are we don't call
ourselves the Fab Seven because we think
we're fabulous
hardly.
Um, we call ourselves the Fab 7 because
we are fabulously blessed.
>> We are fabulously blessed. We own Papa's
special ops team and to we are
fabulously blessed to be together
on this team.
So, um, we we have Chalala, the birthday
girl, who is from Zambia, and Joanne is
from Trinidad. Christina is from
Colorado. Mariselis from Kansas.
Simone is from Virginia. And Birdie is
from Connecticut. TMA
is Birdie
and she's from Connecticut. And I'm
Barb. Barb Simmons. And I am on the
island of Anguila. So even though we are
far from each other,
our hearts are united as we pray as we
pray for Papa Ronnie. It's a blessing.
It's such a blessing. And Christina,
who's a little shy, has looked up all of
the scriptures for this month
on intercessory prayer. So today our
scripture reading from Sister Christina
is Galatians 6:2 and it says, "Bear ye
one another's burdens
and so fulfill the law of Christ."
Let me just give you a little context of
this. I have to practice this because
I'm in the El Moses group where we're
learning to share our faith. So the
context of this verse is that Paul
is writing his closing exhortations
um to the Galatians that the Galatians
were a church in Asia that Paul founded.
And he's urging believers to support
each other in their weakness. He says
the word bear means to carry a heavy
load like helping someone with a
physical or an emotional weight. Um, and
burdens are referred to as the
struggles, sins or trials fellow
Christians face.
Things that are too heavy for one person
alone. But by sharing these, the church
acts as a united body, not isolated
individuals. And we want to be a united
body. So this command fulfills the law
of Christ, which is selfless love. When
we lift a brother's load, we reflect
Christ's sacrifice.
His love becomes active in us and it
turns duty into grace empowered service.
And just just a spoiler alert, I got
this from photog.
So it's a fabulous website. Go to it and
learn about it. So today we are going to
I'm going to tell you the prayer
requests that were in the chat
and Sister Birdie is going to pray over
these prayers.
So these requests. So, um, the first one
we're going to say is, and I just want
to tell you that if you're pray, if you
put a prayer request in the chat and you
don't hear us mention it
while we're praying, that doesn't mean
we didn't get it and it doesn't mean
we're not taking care of it. It means
that we will pray over these prayer
requests all during the week and we will
pray over these prayer requests until
you tell us they have been answered. So,
>> Amen.
>> Our first prayer request is for a happy
birthday for our sister Chilala. She,
like we told you, she is one of the Fab
Seven and we ask that may the Lord bless
her on her day today. And we also pray
for healing for sister Joanne and for
sister Jessica because we know that our
Jehovah Rafa can heal all things. And
Jason Diggs 9106 is asking for unspoken
prayer. So Lord, you know what is on his
heart. Answer his prayers. And our
brother Artel Peters is asking for his
Bible study prayer for his Bible study
brother Moathananiel Parker to receive
shelter and work as well as support and
healing. And he needs s brother Parker
needs sustainability in his faith above
all.
And yella
casses 7
is says pray for Jamie who has stage
four cancer and Teresa who has health
issues and all of her kids who are sick
now especially Jackie Jasmine and
herself who have lung issues because of
COVID.
And Nicole Curtis asks us to please pray
for her mom Tony who is dealing with
many issues
um
with her family, many issues with her
family and caring for Nicole's
grandmother.
And our sister Takara asks to continue
to pray for all her sons, especially
Omar Omarian Oteno, who is 21 years old,
and for James Bumpus, her brother, whom
she has, James Pumpus, Bumpus III, whom
she has not seen in 10 years. Dara
misses him and would like to hear from
him.
Erica Esgridge 6856 is asking for prayer
for all she is going through. So Lord be
with her and we um we ask you to pray
for to soften people's hearts to donate
laptops to the LOC benef benevolence
department
and Marisella Johnson is asking for
families
prayer for families for every home
represented
letting your presence bring harmony love
and faith and to unite us by your love
and bless our marriages and may be may
they may you be
the center of our love. Fact seven is
asking for prayer for the tech team for
all their hard work and all they do.
There's a lot of plates spinning in the
background that we don't know about and
that they are spinning those plates. So
we ask you to pray for them. And we
lastly ask for prayers for our pastor
and for the message that the Lord has
sent him to deliver today.
>> Amen.
>> Okay Birdie.
>> Amen. Amen. Amen. Praise God. Happy
Sabbath brothers and sister across the
globe. This another beautiful, beautiful
day, another Sabbath day of rest. And we
are grateful to lift up all these
beautiful prayer requestes to the throne
of God because we have a God who sees
and a God who hears and a God who
answers according to his word.
>> And now dear Lord, as we pray, take her
hearts and mind far away from the
presence of the world all around to the
throne where grace does abound. May her
lives be transformed by your loves. May
her soul be refreshed from above. At
this moment, let people everywhere join
us now as we come to D in prayer. Most
gracious and heavenly father, today we
want to lift up all these beautiful
prayer requests to you. We trust in you,
oh God, to hear and to answer because
you are a God that sees and you're a God
that hears. And there are so many
issues, so many situations, so many
circumstances that we, your sons and
your daughter faces. But this morning,
oh God, across the globe and this
beautiful Sabbath day of rest, as I lift
up these prayer requests to you, you're
a God that here burdens are lifting at
Calvary and Jesus is very near. As Psalm
55 and verse 22 said, "Cause our burdens
and upon God, and he will sustain thee."
And that's exactly what we're doing. We
are causing our burden of a father at
the foot of the cross. We are spreading
the issues of our brothers and sisters
upon the alther at this very present
moment in time. Jeremiah 33 and:E3 said,
"Call unto me and hide. God will hear
and answer." Heavenly Father, I pray
this very present moment that there are
some that are suffering from affliction,
from sickness, from disease, from
cancer, from arthritis, from diabetes,
oh father, physical sickness, oh God.
But you are the great healer. You're the
great physician who reach out your arms
of grace and mercy across the globes to
your sons and your daughter. When you
walk planet hurt, there was no sickness
that was bringing to your care that you
did not heal, oh God. And you're the
same yesterday, today, and forever. And
that's why we are laying these sickness,
these brothers and sister, they are your
sons and your daughter. You created
them. You know them of a father from the
crown of their head to the sole of their
feet. So whatever they are facing this
morning, this moment, this night for
some of them across the globe, you the
great physician, I pray oh God that you
will breathe your holy spirit each and
in each and every one of their lives. I
pray that your cleansing blood will
reach and flood every bloodstream from
the crown of their head to the sole of
their feet. Touch every organs and every
muscles across their bodies. Oh God, I
pray that you will uproot and annihilate
every sickness and every diseases out of
their system, out of their body. Oh
father, I pray that you will he aching
giants, their he aching muscles. Oh
father, whatever they are suffering from
this moment. Oh father, we know that
they have earthly doctors, earthly
physician that give them medication, but
we know God without your help, they
cannot do the things that you allow
these doctor to do. of a father. You are
the one who give them the brain and the
intelligence. So I pray, oh God, that as
they minister to your sons and daughter,
oh God, according to your willpower of a
father, the medicine will reach deep
down into their hearts into the late
line, into their muscles of a father and
that you will bring healing to them. But
we know that the full healing, the true
healing comes from you, the cleansing
blood of Jesus Christ. In James 5:68, we
must pray favorably. We must lift up
everything to the throne of God. We must
not stop when we pray for him. We must
continue knocking at the door of our
Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. He never
get tired of us. We can always come to
him 24/7. Whatever time of the day we
call upon our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ, he hears and he answer because
he said when we call and even before we
open up our mouth, he already answer our
prayers. First John 5 and verse14 said
pray with confidence asking God and when
we ask he promised that he will give us
the help he will heal us and this
morning oh God this evening this
afternoon this night for some of us oh
God we are claiming healing oh God we
refuse to let go until we get the
healing from you Lord Jesus when we ask
you here you answer whatever your answer
is sometime you say yes sometime you say
immediately sometime you say no sometime
You say wait, but you always answer. So
whatever the answer is, we give you
thanks and praise. You said they that
wait upon the Lord shall renew their
strength. So if you answer in saying
wait, I pray oh God that you will give
your brothers and sister, your sons and
daughter across the globe how to
patiently wait upon you as you bring the
healing in their life and if his
financial blessing with his job aba
father until they get that answer oh
God. So we give you thanks and praise
for your grace, for your mercy today,
for everything that you're doing and you
hear the cries of those in the chat. So
father there are so many requests and
there was one that I picked out John a
haba father alley 1997
and he was asking for asking you aba
father to help him to stop smoking aba
father you're the god that can stop that
addiction oh god and I am laying Johnny
easily at the foot of your cross and
that smoking oh god in the mighty name
of Jesus that you will flush it out of
his system oh god that you will flush
every smoking habit away from him down
into the flush pin over a father
wherever you need to flush it out. Flush
it out from the crown of his head and to
the sole of his feet. Remove that
addiction of smoking from him. So he
will have no taste, no appetite. Every
time he feels smoking, he will take up
your words. And if he don't have the
strength to read, he may put it on a
gadget and turn it on and let it listen
and listen to it or he may play a song
something over father. I plead the blood
of Jesus and when he feels smoking over
a father he can take a lovely fresh
natural organic fruit and take a bite in
an orange and a apple in a grape in a
plum something to help to quench that
addiction from the smoke. So I pray God
in Jesus name that you will uproot it
and nihilate it from his stream from his
taste buds so you have no more taste for
that smoking habit in the mighty name of
Jesus because I know that's not from you
in Jesus name and the body belongs to
you. It is your temple and you want Jan
body to be kept clean. And I pray oh God
like when you walk planet earth oh God
and you walk in the earthly temple and
you turn over every ungodly and filthy
things. Remove the ungodly smoking away
from your dear son at this very present
moment and time. And I pray the baptism
power of the Holy Spirit to continue to
breathe upon John right now in Jesus
name. And for the rest remaining of his
life. I also want to pray for Michaela
Benson
um who is in the hospital and his
husband was asking for prayers. Aba
father whatever she's going through Gay
Benston aba father I pray right now for
Michaela Benson aba father wrap her up
in the hollow palm of your hands oh god
reach out in that hospital room where
she's at aba father from the crown of
her head and to the sole of her feet
dispatch your holy angel be with the
nurses the doctor and all caregiver all
hands that is on deck and I pray oh god
in the mighty and precious name of our
lord and savior Jesus Christ for healing
in your dear daughter sister Michaela
this Michaela Benson at this very
special moment in time and for her
husband to put that request in the chat
in Jesus name al and that she have many
seizure within a week about 78 seizure
that's a lot of seizure of a father I
pray that you will come and annihilate
and uproot all those seizure from her
body and give her the healing that she
need even right now in Jesus name we
want to continue to lift up sister Eden
to you aba father you know exactly who
sister Eden is continue to wrap her up
in the holo palm of your hands oh God, I
pray that you will continue to breathe
your Holy Spirit upon your dear daughter
across the globe, wherever she is, as
you continue to bring healing and late
and uproot every dynamic forces away
from her life. Oh God, I claim her heart
for you. I claim her life for you
totally and thoroughly. And at the end
of her day, aba father, I pray that her
life will be well pleasing to you, aba
father, so that she will make it home
into your glorious kingdom when you
shall come in the clouds of glory. give
the family the rest and the peace that
passes all human understanding that they
need as they continue to go through what
sister Eden is going through at this
very present moment in time. I also want
to lift up sister Astria Aba father
Boland um daughter um mother aba father
wife who is 71 aba father who suffering
from astrosis aba father I pray in the
mighty and precious name of her lord and
savior Jesus Christ that you will reach
out oh god you know how our dear sister
Astria love to do ministry work working
in the pantry and doing um field service
for you Lord Jesus and because of the
aches and pain in her body in her joints
oh God and the osteoporosis She is not
able to do it. Oh father, it's stirring
up her system. So God, I pray in the
mighty and precious name of Jesus that
you will reach out and touch her body.
Oh father, strengthen down mo those
muscle. Oh God, put your hands of touch
around her, Lord. Wrapped her up in your
hollow pawn of those big agape arms of
yours even this very present moment and
time and bring healing and comfort and
to your dear daughter, sister Astria
right now. Want to continue to pray for
sister Joan Father, our dear sister
Jojo. You know her by name and by
number. Not a strong one of her year is
missing. And she's in the beautiful
highland of Trinidad and Tobago. And we
lay her up in the hollow palm of your
hands right now. She is watching Aba
Father. I pray in the mighty name of
Jesus. Breathe your holy spirit in that
household which she and her families aba
father and dispatch your holy angel oh
God and encircle around them as you
continue to bring them joy and goodness
and blessing in the mighty and precious
name of our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ. remember your daughter and our
sister, Sister Takara, at this very
present moment in time. Oh God, you know
all about your dear daughter, Sister
Takara. She's a powerhouse for you. Oh
God, I pray that you will continue to
wrap her up in the hollow palm of your
hands and her family. Oh God, her two
sons, oh God, and the rest remaining of
her family. You know everything that
she's facing at this moment and what
she's going through. But God, you're the
God of that heals and you're the God
that have sister Takara and her family
in the hollow palm of your hands. Oh
God, I pray that those two young son of
hers, oh God, I pray you will breathe
your Holy Spirit in and around their
life. Oh God, and I pray that you will
bring them out of the world and draw
them closer to your precious bleeding
side. I pray that your Holy Spirit, oh
God, will wrap them up, oh God. That
they have no taste, no h for this world,
oh God, because this world is full of
sin, shame, and disgrace, oh God. And I
pray that they will go to you of a
father and that they will give their
heart to you, a mother's prayer, oh God.
So I pray as you continue to answer the
prayer of sister Takara for her two sons
and for the rest remaining of her family
of a father and a uncle of hers that has
been missing or a brother that has been
missing for many many years. Oh God, I
pray in the mighty and precious name of
Jesus, you know exactly where that
family member of sister Takara is. Oh
God, wherever he is at this moment, oh
God, if he's still alive, oh God, I pray
that the Holy Spirit will prick his
heart, oh God, and let him know that his
family members really concerned about
him, oh God, some way, somehow, bring
him home to the family, oh God, I pray
in the mighty and precious name of our
Lord and Savior Jesus Christ, remember
our dear daughter, your dear daughter
and her sister, sister Curtis, at this
very present moment in time who is
asking for prayer for herself, her
family, her father, mother and
grandmother. Lord, you know everything
that's going on in and around Sister
Curtis life and her family. I lay them
all in the hollow palm of your hands.
Those big copy arms of yours that can
wrap the whole world in it. Oh God, I
pray that you will pour out your love,
your spirit, and healing touches and
sister um Curtis and her family at this
very present moment and time as they
continue to hold firm to you, oh God,
knowing that you will never leave them
nor forsake them. There are some, oh
God, who are suffering from
spirituality, oh God, who need more
spiritual strength. I pray that you will
breathe your holy spirit upon them and
strengthen them across the globe. Some
are suffering from mental illness,
emotional and personal. Oh God, wrap
them all up in the hollow palm of your
hands this moment. Breathe your holy
spirit of rest and comfort. You are the
God who bring healing. You are the God
who said we should come to you just as
we are. And when we come and lay them in
the hands of yours at the foot of your
cross and spread the issues upon your
altar, your promises that even before we
open up our mouth and utter our words
that you already hear and that you
already answer and by faith I come and
behalf of all these my brothers and
sister, let nothing on my part stop or
ender these prayer requests from
reaching into your store room of grace
and mercy. Angel are descending up and
down that ladder bringing these prayer
requests into your into your kingdom. of
a father, the gra the throne room of
grace. And I pray, oh God, that as they
reach to you, oh God, you will send down
the blessing upon each and every
individual, whatever their situation or
circumstances may be, maybe spiritual,
financial, physical, emotionally,
personally, whatever it is, oh God, I
lay them all in the palm of your hands.
And remember the kids, oh God, the kids
across the globe, Baba Father, the kids
of living manner, I lift them up into
your hallow hands. Oh God, breathe your
love and your holy spirit all over their
life even right now because they're
living in a world that is so sick. Oh,
father, sick of sin, shame, and
disgrace. Oh God, and unfortunately some
of the kids are falling. I plead the
blood of Jesus over their life, oh God.
I pray that you will remove every evil
from them, oh God. I pray that your holy
spirit will wrap around them, oh God,
wherever they may be. and that the holy
angel from heaven will dispatch and
encircle around them and protect them
from all harms and danger wherever they
may be in school in home or they may be
just walking on the street wherever. Oh
God, cover them because they need your
guidance and your protection. Oh God, I
plead the blood of Jesus over their life
at this moment. I continue to pray for
blade of hope ministry. I lift up the
blade of hope ministry to you at this
very present moment in time. You know
exactly what the blade of hope
ministries. It is a ministry from
brother Terry God and many others and I
lay it in the hollow palm of your hands
that you will just continue to work on
the blade of hope ministry of a father.
It's a ministry that it when it's
finished or father it will be beautiful
and magnificent and it's to open up a a
sanctuary where prisoners who are coming
out of prison will have a home a safe
home a godly home where they can come
and dwell after many years in a dark
place. They can come to a place full of
light. Not only work, not only the light
of the sunshine, but spiritual light.
And they will have a healthy meal night
and day, spiritually, physically and
emotionally. So continue to wrap your
arms around the blade of hope ministry
as you continue to use each and everyone
that is on board at this very present
moment in time. And as they come to
gather over, Father, I pray that your
dwelling, your holy spirit will continue
to wrapped around the board of and the
board of ministry and the blade of hope
ministry at this very present moment and
time. I continue to pray for all the
tech teams, oh father, and all the
equipment, those who are working and
serving behind the scene right here on
the living mana platform, aba father, to
make sure that this beautiful worship go
across the globe so that your sons, your
daughters can hear the breath of life,
the good news, aba father, the gospel
message father. So touch their gadget,
touch their room wherever they may be,
their laptop, their phone, their
computers and allow them to work not
just for today but constantly and
continually each and every time and be
with them and their family in a very
mighty and powerful way in the mighty
and magnificent name of Jesus Christ. We
also continue to lift up brother Terry
and sister Amra before you aba father
the prayer team leader aba father you
know them by name and number stranger I
lay them in the hollow palm of your
hands night and day 24/7 wrap them
around in your hollow palm of your hands
oh God as you continue to send out the
showers of blessing all over their life
every step of the journey way that
they're traveling as we all travel this
pilgrim ground here and we continue to
lift up to the aba father the beautiful
service from your dear man's servant oh
god you know exactly the words that you
have laid upon his heart. Oba Father,
Pastor Hiver Myers, your son, you know
him by name and you know him by number
from he was in the womb. Your anointing,
you call him a father for such a time as
this, aba father. And at the right time
in his younger teenager years, oh God,
you pull him out of the world into this
your beautiful partway of life, oh God,
into the revenant church to do this
gospel work for you, aba father, to
spread your words, your good news across
the globe, aba father. And today the
message that you have for him to spread,
oh father, it's the living bread that
will go across this beautiful globe
father where your sons, your sons and
daughter will hear and their heart will
be renewed and be transferred. Father
his word today the living manner will
all be about love above father. The
world today celebrate love but every day
is the love day in the our lord and
savior Jesus Christ because god is the
big agape love with Jesus Christ he is
the true love. He came and hang upon the
cross. The cross is the love at all time
for our life. So we know that whatever
pastor meer's sermon is even though it
say love is sermon we never can tell
what it's going to be like. Oh God, we
just sit back and relax as we dine and
enjoy around the beautiful table of love
from your man's servant to fill our
hearts and our mind and our soul to
continue to go through the rest
remaining of this beautiful Sabbath day
and the rest remaining of the week. So
touch him aba father touch his equipment
aba father touch his tutor room aba
father everything touch the heara father
remove every and anything that will
enter this beautiful work this beautiful
sermon from go across the globe today
aba father wrap him up in the hollow
palm of your hands at this very present
moment and time but not only this moment
oh God but forever and ever wherever he
may be by land here or sea I pray oh God
that you will continue to edge and fence
him around and when I pray for pastor
Myers I pray for is beautiful bride
sister tante too because they are one.
So whatever go for one go for both of
them. So wrap them up in their household
in the mighty and precious and
magnificent name of our Lord and Savior
Jesus Christ. And Lords of Lee, I
continue to pray for all of us as the
prayer warrior warrior across the living
manner platform because daily, weekly,
momently, every day, we lift up before
the throne of God your prayer request
that you place in the chat nights and
day. Whatever chats you put it on,
whether you put it on during this
Sabbath hour or you put it on during the
course of the week in different chats,
over Father, we lift them up to you and
we thank you, oh God. So pour your pour
your holy spirit all over us oh God and
give us the strength that we need to go
from day to day so that we can continue
to do this beautiful work that you have
called each and every one of us to do at
such a time as this that we are living
in planet earth. And if ever we need to
pray it is no other time than now. And
when all is said and done, we all are
here traveling the journey. And we pray
and hope that when you shall come in the
clouds of glory, whether we are
arresting or whether we are alive, we'll
be up in the first resurrection where we
will all caught up together to meet you
in the clouds of glory. And heavenly
father, thank you very much for your
goodness and for your grace and for your
mercy that your holy spirit is flood all
over our life right now as we continue
to journey through this pilgrim ground
that we are traveling. Thank you for
hearing and answering and whatever I
fought you this moment which are many
fade it not to grant it unto these your
sons and your daughter of a father but
bind us up all with your card of love
and unbrokenness at such a time as this.
Hear and answer all these beautiful
cries. These another wonderful mercies I
humbly seek in the worthy and precious
name of our Lord and Savior Jesus
Christ. Let us sit back, relax as we
enjoy and dine from the beautiful
banquet table the message of love from
the messenger, Pastor Hyram Myers. In
Jesus holy word name I pray. Amen. And
amen.
>> Amen.
>> Thank you.
I need you.
You need me.
We're all a part of God's body.
Stand with me.
Agree with me. We're all a part of God's
body.
It is his will that every need be
supplied.
You are important
to me. I need you to survive.
I need you.
You need me.
We're all a part of God's body.
Stand with me.
Agree with me. We're all a part of God's
body.
It is his will that every need be
supplied.
You are important
to me. I need you to survive.
I pray for you. You pray for me. I love
you. I need you to survive. I won't harm
you with words from my mouth. I love
you. I need you to survive. I pray for
you. You pray for me. I love you. I need
you to survive. I won't harm you.
You pray for me.
I love you. I need you to survive. I
pray for you. You pray for me. I love
you. I need you to survive. I won't harm
you with words from my mouth. I love
you. I need you to survive. I pray for
you. You pray for me. I love you. I need
you to survive. I won't harm you with
words from my mouth. I love you. I need
you to survive.
It is his will that every need be
supplied.
You are important
to me. I need you to survive.
Happy Sabbath, church family. Um,
we are getting ready to get into the
word of God this morning, this
afternoon, I should say. Um, I want to
again welcome uh each one of you. And um
number one, put a one in the chat if
you're ready to get into the living mana
for the day. Number two, uh I'm going to
uh ask you to go ahead and hit that
share
uh button. Share this link. Um let
people know that the sermon um for the
day is about to begin. And uh the title
of the message uh is a love story. Um I
believe that God has something very
special to say to his people um through
this message today. And so I'm going to
invite you to pray with me uh as we jump
into this message. Let's do that now.
Heavenly Father, we are coming before
you today asking Lord in a very special
way that you would please speak um to
your people today Lord. Um Lord open our
eyes, give us wisdom, insight and
understanding and above all Lord
um bring conviction to our hearts and uh
may we Lord learn to follow you to love
you uh as you have loved us. We pray
this in Jesus name. Amen. Amen. Um, a
love story. A love story. Today's
message, if I were to simplify it, is is
really just about letting you know um
just how much God loves you. And there
are a couple of different aspects we're
going to look at in this message today
which really for most of you will be
nothing new but perhaps for all of you
you will see things in a new light. We
will just say old truth in a new way.
And uh what we're going to do today
everyone is we're going to begin. We're
going to go to the screen and we're
going to begin with a parable uh that is
uh two verses long and that most of us
are familiar with and most of us have a
particular understanding of this verse.
Let's go to the screen and um
we're going to look at Matthew chap 13
45 and 46. The Bible says again, "The
kingdom of heaven is likened unto a
treasure hid in the field,
the which when a man has found, he
hideth for joy thereof,
and goeth and sell all that he has, and
buyth that field." Again, the kingdom of
heaven is likened to a merchant man
seeking goodly pearls, who when he had
found one pearl of great price, went and
sold all that he had and bought it. I
want to focus on that last uh the last
parable. The kingdom of heaven being
like unto a merchant man
um seeking goodly pearls. when he finds
one pearl of great price, he goes away.
He sells all that he has to buy it. And
um as we look at this verse, I think we
are all reminded of the importance
um of
giving all up for Jesus. How many of you
can say amen to that? Put that one in
the chat. uh if you understand the
significance of what it means to give it
all up for Jesus that is what conversion
is. It is it is being moved to sell
everything that we have. Um and we
typically understand this parable as a
call uh to to uh the individual to leave
all behind to follow Christ. And we
actually see this an example of this in
Matthew the 19th chapter. I will begin
reading from verse 16 where the Bible
says, "Now behold, one came and said to
him,"Good teacher, what good things
shall I do that I may have eternal
life?" And he said unto him, "Why do you
call me good? No one is good but one,
that is God. But if you will enter into
life, keep the commandments."
He said to him, "Which ones?" Jesus
said, "You shall not murder. You shall
not commit adultery. You shall not
steal. You shall not bear false witness.
Honor your father and your mother, and
love your neighbor as yourself. The
young man said to him, "All these things
have I kept from my youth. What do I
still lack?" Jesus said unto him, "If
you want to be perfect, go and sell what
you have and give to the poor, and you
will have treasure in heaven, and come
follow me."
But when the young man heard that
saying, he went away sorrowful, for he
had great possessions.
And so we see here a a a good
illustration of this, right? That that
there is an individual who wants to be
saved, who wants to have eternal life,
but he is unwilling to sell all. And so
when we read this parable,
we are immediately
uh uh confronted
many times with the idea of us having to
give it all up for Jesus. Let me ask
you, put a five in the chat if when you
read that you struggle like this rich
young ruler. walking in in in the spirit
uh requires warfare and to give it all
up for Jesus is not a light thing. It's
not something that is easily done.
Um however,
there is there is a problem
with this approach to the parable.
It is not an incorrect approach to the
parable, but I would say it is an
incomplete approach to the parable.
And you may wonder, well, why is that?
Well, let's look again at the parable.
In the parable, the merchant man is
seeking after goodly pearls.
And we are immediately faced with a
challenge in the way that we typically
understand this parable. Because if we
take this parable the way that we
usually understand it, it means that we
have been going out
seek there is none that seeketh after
God. Let me read it again. As it is
written God. Let me read it again. As it
is written, there is none righteous,
know not one. There is none that
understandeth. There is none that
seeketh after God. So if this is true,
then beloved, what I want to suggest to
you is that the parable that we've just
heard
represent an unbelieving person seeking
God.
Y'all put a put a put a one in the chat
if you understand the point that I just
made. I like how Christy put it. Christy
5791. No one is born seeking God. Right?
No one is born seeking God. This is a
very crucial point to understand.
In fact, in Psalms 14:2,
the Bible says, "The Lord lookketh down
or looked down from heaven upon the
children of men to see if there were any
that did understand and seek God."
1 Corinthians chapter 2:14 tells us
this, "But the natural man receiveth not
the things of the spirit of God, for
they are foolishness unto him, neither
can he know them, because they are
spiritually discerned." So I want to
suggest to you today
that the the the the the challenge with
this parable in thinking that you are
the merchant man at least initially that
you are the merchant seeking goodly
pearls and when you found it you're
supposed to go sell everything you have
and buy it. The initial problem with
that is that there is none that seeketh
after God.
That the natural man receives not the
things of God, for they are spiritually
discerned. The natural man cannot
discern what a goodly pearl is.
Are y'all following? Are you
understanding what I'm saying? If
there's none that seek after God, if if
if if the natural man receives not the
things of God, then this merchant man,
the the merchant who is looking for
goodly pearls
cannot in its initial sense
represent you and me.
Well, if not, pastor, what are you
saying? I I want to show you beloved who
this merchant man in the parable
primarily represents.
In Luke 19:10, the Bible says, "For the
Son of Man is come to seek and to save
that which was lost."
May I suggest to you that the merchant
man who is going out looking for goodly
pearls, he's a merchant man by
employment, by trade. This is his job.
That that merchant man is none other
than Jesus Christ himself.
He is the one that is going out looking
for the goodly pearl.
We're talking about a love story today
and that's the picture I want to paint
for you that Jesus is in fact the
merchant initially. I'm coming to
something very important. So please keep
following.
Let me show you another example. Luke
15:4.
What man of you having a hund sheep if
he lose one of them does not leave the
99 in the wilderness and go after that
which is lost until he find it. And when
he has found it, he laid it on his
shoulders, rejoicing. And when he cometh
home, he calleth together his friends
and neighbors, saying unto them, Rejoice
with me, for I have found my sheep which
was lost.
I say unto you that likewise joy shall
be in heaven over one sinner that
repenteth, more than over 99 just
persons which need no repentance.
Then he goes on to say, "Either what
woman having 10 pieces of silver if she
lose one piece does not light a candle
and sweep the house and seek diligently
till she find it." May I suggest that in
this parable,
Jesus is the merchant man who is looking
for that thing, that valuable thing,
that pearl of great price.
And so now you might say, "Well, pastor,
what is this pearl that Jesus would be
looking for?" Come with me again to the
book of Malachi 3:1 17 where God
describes his people where he says, "And
they shall be mine, say the Lord of
hosts, in that day when I shall make up
my jewels, and I will spare them spare
them as a man spareth his own son that
serveth him." In other words, beloved,
the pearl of great price
in the eyes of Jesus
was you and I.
Let me say that again.
I I need you to catch this and lock this
into your mind.
The pearl of great price
that the merchant man
sees as valuable
is a symbol
of me.
It is a symbol of you.
You are that pearl of great price. In
other words, beloved, in essence, the
pearl is a person and that person is
you. Now, please don't get me wrong. I
understand how you have always heard
this parable and we're coming there
because it is not wrong. But I'm trying
to show you how we get to that place in
the first place. It doesn't begin with
you going out looking for Jesus. It
begins. It began with Jesus coming
looking for you.
Are y'all with me so far?
Now, I want to explain to you how a
pearl is created.
A pearl forms when an irritant, usually
a parasite or debris, not just sand,
enters an oyster's soft tissue. As the
oyster is unable to expel that irritant,
listen to me y'all.
The oyster protects itself by
secretreting macro, which is also known
as mother of the p, mother of pearl, a
substance made from calcium carbonate
and protein. Layer upon layer is is
basically formed around this irritant.
Over time through pressure, through pain
and repeated coating from its own body,
the wound is encapsulated and
transformed
into a pearl.
I need you to catch the significance of
this.
In an environment
that is otherwise good and functioning
correctly, an irritant enters that
environment
and the response
is what produces a pearl. Why is that
significant everyone? Because I want you
to understand this.
Not only is the pearl a person, Jesus
did not just come just say, "Hey, I
found an individual that is that is that
is valuable to me." But I want to
suggest to you that the pearl is also
our planet.
In Genesis 1 verse one, the Bible says,
"In the beginning, God created the
heavens and the earth, and the earth was
without form and void, and darkness was
upon the face of the deep. And the
spirit of God moved upon the face of the
waters. And God said, "Let there be
light." and there was light. And so we
see that the you have the creation
process going on in Genesis chapter 1.
In Genesis chapter 2, the Bible says,
"Thus the heavens and the earth were
finished, and all the host of them. And
on the seventh day, God ended his work
which he had made. And he rested on the
seventh day from all his work which he
had made. And God blessed the seventh
day and sanctified it because that in it
he had rested from all his work which
God created and made. So in other words,
beloved, God finished the creation of
the earth. It was good. It was all good.
And then God rested from his work. But
guess what happens? An irritant
entered the planet.
In Genesis 3:es 1, the Bible says, "Now
the serpent was more subtle than any
beast of the field which the Lord God
had made. And he said unto the woman,
"Yay, has God said, Ye shall not eat of
every tree of the garden?" And I want
you to understand, beloved, that when
sin entered into the world, it became an
irritant that mankind could not expel.
So here's the the two things I want you
to lock in in this parable.
If the merchant man is Jesus, then the
pearl is not only you. It is not only me
but it is also this planet.
In other words, Jesus saw something so
valuable in you,
so valuable in me,
so valuable in this world.
Are y'all following me so far? We're
we're breaking this parable down step by
step. I want you to note something. The
merchant is a merchant by trade. In
other words, he's a professional
merchant. He knows market value. He's
not naive. He's not emotionally
impulsive. Right? A merchant will will
normally understand how to diversify
assets. A a merchant will will
understand how to buy inventory
strategically. And a merchant never
liquidates everything for one item. And
yet here we have this merchant who is
not an emotional buyer, not a naive
admirer, not a sentimental figure, but a
cosmic
evaluator of worth.
A divine evaluator of worth.
And this divine evaluator of worth looks
at the pearl and says, "I must have
that."
And
I am willing to sell
all.
Are y'all catching this?
We're getting to how you typically
understand the parable. We're not there
yet. We got to we got to take it this in
in order. In other words, there is a pro
there is another application to this
parable that most of us miss which is
why we struggle with the second part of
the parable which is sell all for Jesus.
Really,
it's because we don't understand
the story in its divine context.
that the original merchant man is Jesus
who saw planet earth who saw you and I
and said all right
this is worth me selling all. So the
text says that he sold all that he had.
Now I I need y'all to kind of pause for
a moment and just think about that.
If you were to sell all that you have,
what would it be? It might be, "Oh, I'm
gonna sell my car. I'm gonna sell my
house. I'm gonna sell my clothing. Um,
I've got, you know, I got a computer.
I've got uh, you know, some equip. I got
some collectibles." Right? Your selling
all um might not mean that much to you,
but it would. No matter how, you know,
little, you're selling all is going to
mean a lot to you. But I want you to
think about the rich man who says,
"Yeah, I'm going to sell all." Now,
comparatively speaking, whoa, I'm going
to give up my, you know, multi-million
dollar mansion. I'm going to give up X,
Y, and Z, you know, etc. Everything that
he has. But in this parable, we're not
talking about
a human merchant.
We're talking about Jesus
before he becomes
manifest in the flesh,
he sells all. So what does that mean?
What what what is it all? What is the
all? Let's go over to the book of
Ezekiel chapter 1 verse 26. Ezekiel
chapter 1 verse 26. We're gonna find
here a description of Jesus. The Bible
says above the firmament there what that
was over their heads was the likeness of
a throne as the appearance of a sapphire
stone and upon the likeness of the
throne was the likenesses appearance of
a man above upon it. Verse 27 and I saw
as the color of amber as the appearance
of fire round about within it from the
appearance of his loins even upward and
from the appearance of his loins even
downward I saw as it were the appearance
of fire and it had brightness before it.
I need y'all to understand something.
That part of what Jesus sold was his
glory.
Let me say it again.
Jesus saw you.
Jesus saw me. Jesus saw this planet. The
merchant saw the pearl and said, "This
pearl is of such value to me that I will
give up my fiery glory. I will give up
my throne." In fact, in 1 Corinthians
chapter 2:9, the Bible tells us, "But as
it is written, eye has not seen nor ear
heard, neither hath entered into the
heart of man the things which God has
prepared for them that love him." So
think about that for a second. If it is
impossible for us to imagine the glory
of heaven,
then I want you to understand in as much
as it is possible that that thing that
you can't imagine is the thing that
Jesus
sold.
In other words, beloved, you cannot even
imagine what he actually gave up. You it
can't come into your mind. Your mind
it does not have the capacity
to imagine
what Jesus gave up for us.
Are y'all following what I'm saying? I
need you to understand your worth in the
eyes of the merchants.
So, so watch this. Not only does does
Jesus give up a a a heaven,
which means he's giving up a place that
we cannot even imagine. Not only does
Jesus give up his glory,
his glowing fiery glory, he becomes a
man. Hebrews chapter 2:1 17, "Wherefore
in all things it behooved him to be made
like unto his brethren, that he might be
a merciful and faithful high priest in
things pertaining to God to make
reconciliation for the sins of the
people." In other words, beloved, Jesus
gave all of that up. He gave up the
place.
He gave up his per He gave up who he was
as an individual and says, "I'm coming
to buy this pearl,
this planet,
and the people on it.
This is how valuable this is to me that
I'm willing to give this all up.
And yet, beloved,
it still doesn't cover all that Jesus
gave up for us. Let me take you to the
book of Philippians chapter 2:5 where
the Bible says, "Let this mind be in you
which was also in Christ Jesus who being
in the form of God thought it not
robbery to be equal with God but made
himself of no reputation and took upon
him the form of a servant and was made
in the likeness of men and being thought
now pause for a second
took upon him the form of a servant and
was made in the likeness of men." If we
stopped right there, the condescension
of Christ, the value which he has just
placed on us, on you,
on you, Mr. Sinner, on you, Mrs. Sinner.
The value he has just placed on you and
on this planet is already immeasurable
simply in the fact that he became a man.
God
became
a man,
laid aside his glory and his divinity to
purchase you,
to purchase me, to purchase this planet.
But the text goes on to say that not
only did he condescend to become a man,
but it ultimately says, "And being found
in fashion as a man, he humbled himself
and became obedient unto death, even the
death of the cross."
Let me say it this way. He sold his life
savings.
May I say that again?
Jesus gave up his life
savings.
Meaning he gave up his life.
He sold all that he had to purchase
you.
Now you understand why this sermon is
called a love story.
Now you understand
what we mean, what I mean,
what the Bible means when it says, "For
God so loved the world, Jesus gave up
his life savings." Now, I want you to
watch this, beloved,
because remember how we talked about the
nacra or the mother of pearl where where
the pearl, listen to me, is the only gem
that is born of a living wound.
The pearl is the only gem
that is created from a living wound.
You see
it is the cross
that creates that encapsulating.
The cross is the The cross is
that substance
that that that begins to cover
the sin that belong to us. begins to
cover the sin that is in this world. It
is what Jesus did on the cross.
In other words, if I can put it this
way, I would let the Bible say it.
Isaiah 53:5, "But he was wounded for our
transgressions. He was bruised for our
iniquities. The chastisement of our
peace was upon him. And with his
stripes, we are healed." Beloved, it is
the death of Jesus that created the
value of you and of me. It is the death
of Jesus that created the value of this
earth. In other words, Jesus said, "I
will buy that pearl even if it kills me.
I must get that pearl even if it kills
me. And it did kill him. In other words,
Jesus was willing to go to the grave for
this pearl of great price. Remember the
pearl is both a person, you, me. The
pearl is also a place this earth. For
God so loved the world that he gave his
only begotten son that whosoever should
believe in him should not perish but
have everlasting life. The pearl of
great price, beloved, was purchased by a
divine merchant who liquidated heaven's
privileges, becoming human
and ultimately giving his life
for that pearl.
Are y'all following so far?
I want you to understand, beloved, how
much Jesus loved you, how much he loves
you, how much he loves me. I need you to
understand
that this is no ordinary love story.
And so Jesus was willing to die for the
pearl.
A and what's powerful is that in his
death, Jesus said something very
interesting. He said, "Listen, h I'm I I
have purchased what I came to buy. I
have purchased what I've come to
purchase.
And now, now that I'm going away, I want
this pearl protected.
My desire
of what I'm going to do with my
property,
I want to protect it.
I love this thing so much. I want to
make sure that after I'm gone, it's
protected. And so, the Bible tells us in
Matthew 26 28. Matthew 26:28. By the
way, let me let me come back to John
3:16 for a second because I need y'all
to get this.
It doesn't say, "For God so loved the
church."
Christian."
It says, "For God so loved the world.
Meaning, beloved, the the very people
that you would think, yeah, there's no
value in them.
Well, God doesn't love those people and
those people and those people and those
people. No, it is precisely for those
people
who we all were at one time or another
or still are even though we might be in
church today.
Jesus died for those people. Gave up all
for those while we were yet sinners.
Christ looked at the pearl and said, "I
know what everybody else is thinking."
You're thinking, "Well, this is no
value. This is corrupt. This is garbage.
This is filth. Destroy it. Get rid of
it. And let's make something new.
No, no, no. Jesus was like, "hm man,
look at that. Look at that." Whereas
whereas others may have said there's no
value, whereas others do say there's no
value, Jesus looked at the pearl
and said, "This thing is so valuable to
me. this planet and the people on it are
so valuable to me that I'm willing to
leave everything and sell it all to come
and buy this with my blood.
And so Jesus says in Matthew 26:28,
"This is the blood of the new testament
which is shed for many for the remission
of sins." So here's what I want you to
see now. Jesus leaves behind a will and
testament. Y'all put a five in the chat
if you understand what I just said.
Jesus leaves behind a will and
testament. He leaves behind a will and
testament. It is called the new
covenant. Why does he leave it behind?
May I suggest to you that the new
covenant is designed to protect the
purchase he just purchased.
Y'all put a nine in the chat if you
understand what I just said. The new
covenant,
the new covenant is Jesus's protection
over the thing he came to buy.
It is Jesus's saying, "This pearl that I
came to die for,
after I leave, I'm going to set set
aside. I'm going to I'm going to to make
parameters
to protect this pearl." The Bible tells
us in Hebrews chapter 9:15, "For this
cause he's the mediator of the New
Testament, that by means of death, for
the redemption of the transgressions
that were under the first testament,
they which are called might receive the
promise of eternal life." And Hebrews
10:16 says, "This is the covenant that I
will make with them after those days,
sayeth the Lord. Uh uh I will put my
laws into their hearts and in their
minds will I write them. It's almost as
if Jesus is saying I'm going to cover
you.
You know like how that pearl is formed
that it basically becomes a shield of of
protection.
Jesus says, "I'm going to cover you
with my covenant."
Please, I want you to understand what I
mean by this.
If the pearl is composed
of people,
if the pearl is is God's redeemed,
then his love for the pearl
leads him to want to protect the pearl.
Let me let me show you what I mean. And
you may be you're you're about to hear
something that you may have never heard
before,
but
in a way you may have never heard it
before, but let me let me let me say it
in this way.
So,
thou shalt not kill. I want to rephrase
that for a moment just so you can get
the idea.
If the pearl is a person,
Jesus came to die for you and for me.
What he's saying now is listen,
do not harm my pearl.
The commandment, thou shalt not kill, is
d it's it's it's Jesus setting a
warning. Listen to me y'all. It is
Jesus's love setting a warning. Listen,
this is my pearl. That person right
there is my pearl that I bought. Do not
harm him.
It's almost as if this commandment, thou
shalt not kill, is God warning, saying
that that person belongs to me.
Are y'all catching this?
The do not kill is is not so much about
this is what righteousness is. Yes, it
is that. But beloved, in a greater
sense, it is Jesus saying, "Hands off my
pearl,
Satan.
Do not harm my pearl.
Do not harm my pearls. Do not harm my
gems." And and even when he gives us the
commandment,
I want you to understand what he's
doing.
It's almost as if he's warning us, "Do
not ever
do not ever put a hand on any of my
pearls
to do them harm."
You know how if you're a parent, put
your hand, put a one in the chat if
you're a parent. Put a one in the chat
if you're a parent.
And um you know how parents do right?
A parent is like
do not
lay a hand on my child.
That's what the parent says. And and
that command to others not to lay a hand
on his child is not for them to you know
well this means you're righteous if you
don't lay a hand on my child. It is
strictly out of love for the child.
So, so I'm going somewhere with this,
y'all. What I want you to understand,
what I'm what I'm what I'm trying to get
you to see is that commandment, do not
kill, is literally God saying, "Do not
harm or touch that which I died for." So
now the question is, well, who did Jesus
die for? The church? No, he died for the
whole world. Therefore, the command do
not kill is a command that is applicable
to every human being on the planet.
How about do not commit adultery?
How about that commandment? You know
what that's saying?
In that commandment, God is again, he's
doing the same thing he did it with with
the thou shalt not kill. He's saying,
"Listen, that is my child. Do not take
from him or from her
husband,
his wife.
That's my child.
Don't touch their spouse."
Once again, beloved, that that
commandment is not God saying here, it's
listen, it's not God saying, "Here's how
you can be righteous." He's simply
saying, "I died for this person and I I
am Do not harm the person I died for."
Are y'all getting the picture?
Do not steal. Yeah. Don't steal from the
apple. Don't steal from the person that
I died for because that is the pearl of
great price. I died for that person.
That law, beloved, is applicable to
every human being on the planet. God
says, "I died for that sinner. I died
for that sinner. I died for that
sinner." Do not once again once again
when we look at these commandments and
we tend to think of these commandments
as this is God telling me here's how you
can be righteous in a sense. Okay,
I'm not opposed to that. But what I am
saying is that the same way if I have my
brothers and I say to somebody look do
not touch my brother and don't mess with
his stuff and don't try to come bear
false witness against him. All of that
is not my concern of hey I'd like you to
be holy you know by doing this you're
not my no that is that's my brother
that's my friend
and now I want you to understand beloved
that God is saying that thing about
every human being on the planet.
The byproduct of that is that you're
living a righteous life. Yes. But
understand that this is flowing. This is
love flowing from the heart of God
saying it. Listen, you remember when God
put that Cain, that mark upon Cain
cuz Cain was like, I'm guilty and now
people whoever finds me is going to kill
me. And God puts a mark on Cain so that
nobody would kill him.
I need y'all to understand, beloved,
the the the
amazing love of God demonstrated there.
Cain has just killed Abel.
God's going to put a mark on Cain and
say, "Nobody kill him."
I need you to understand, beloved, that
God's love
for the world extends to the whole
planet.
And so when God is giving these
commandments, they are commandments
designed to protect that which he has
purchased with his own blood. Don't
steal from what I've purchased. Don't
bear false witness against what I've
purchased. Don't desire to take what to
take from him what I've purchased. Uh
don't desire to to covet that which
belongs to him whom I have purchased.
And beloved, that applies to everybody.
When people try to get rid of the Ten
Commandments, they literally have no
idea what they're doing. Even down to
Jesus saying, "Honor your mother and
father." It's him saying, "You know, you
know, you know that me and your mom and
your dad, you know that me and your
mother and father that they are mine
and you will honor them
because they're mine.
I bought them. I paid for them
with my own blood.
Beloved, understand this. Understand
this. When when God says when God gives
the Sabbath commandment, he's literally
like, "You're not going to run that
which I have bought into the ground.
You're not going to slave that which I
have bought into the ground. They will
have rest. Do not overwork. You look at
you go through all the commandments. Do
not be do not uh have any other gods
before me." What he's saying is look as
the pearl that pearl belongs to me.
That's why I want you to have no other
gods because I bought you. Nobody else
bought you. I bought you. You are mine.
Therefore,
therefore, you're not going to worship
graven images. Therefore, you're not
going to have any any other gods before
you because no other god loves you the
way that I do. No other god bought you
or redeemed you. You are mine. I love
you and I will do all to protect you.
Are y'all following?
So now we can begin to understand,
beloved, that these commandments do
truly represent the fulfillment of the
law, which is love.
God said, "I love you so much that I'm
putting out a decree that no one will
kill you. No one can kill you. No one
can li can lie about you. No one can
steal from you. And if they do so, they
will answer to me. Can you imagine that?
The Ten Commandments is God's love
towards you.
Is God's protection towards you? Now,
who in the world would want to get rid
of that?
Who in the world would want to get rid
of God's protection over his people?
That is absolute madness, beloved. Now,
I want to show you the end result
because we're still building. We're
still building stuff. I want to show you
the end result of this love. You see,
God Jesus is doing something amazing
here. Come on. Let's go back to the
screen. So, watch what the end result
is. Okay. In in Revelation, let me go
through Revelation
chapter 20. Chapter 21. Watch this. And
he carried me away in the spirit to a
great and high mountain, and showed me
that great city, the holy Jerusalem,
descending out of heaven from God,
having the glory of God. And her light
was like unto a stone most precious,
even like a jasper stone, clear as
crystal. Watch this. Verse 21. And the
12 gates were 12 pearls. Every several
gate was of one pearl and the street of
the city was pure go gold gold as it was
transparent. I want y'all to understand
something.
The end result,
the end result of the divine merchant
coming to this world to purchase this
pearl, to purchase you and me, to
purchase this planet was in essence to
bring heaven to earth.
In other words, the reason why the city
has all these pearlike features to it is
because what Jesus is showing us is this
was the ultimate plan of the merchant
coming to buy and redeem the pearl of
great price. Ultimately so that the
father and his children, Jesus and his
people could be together in the kingdom
of heaven. Let me un let me help you
understand.
When man sinned,
Jesus left heaven because he didn't
count heaven a place to be while man was
lost.
And so the end result of the merchant
coming to buy the pearl is so that by
the end of time, the pearl is God's
people dwelling with God in the city of
heaven.
Beloved, this is why Jesus said in John
14:2, "In my father's house are many
mansions. If it were not so, I would
have told you. I go to prepare a place
for you." The place he he went to
prepare for us. The things that he did,
the thing that he did in giving up his
his life to purchase the pearl, beloved,
is was ultimately so that we could be
with him in the kingdom of heaven. Now,
now
we have just set the stage for one very
simple truth.
Here it is. 1 John 4:19.
We love him
because he first loved us.
We love him because he first loved us.
Not he loved us because we first loved
him. Let me change these words around.
We seek him
because
he first sought us.
Do y'all catch this?
When we read this parable that a
merchant
went forth looking for goodly pearls, we
must understand that initially we're not
that merchant. We're not looking for
goodly pearls. We were not looking for
goodly pearls. We were not seeking the
Lord. We were not seeking these gems.
No, no, no, no, no. We were minding our
own business. We were doing our own
thing. The merchant man in the parable
in its stage one of the parable is Jesus
Christ who saw us who saw planet earth
who saw mankind fallen in sin who saw
the irritant entering into this world
and said I will come and redeem them and
redeem this planet and I will
demonstrate my love for them by showing
how much I left behind
to buy the pearl of great Christ.
And in doing so, beloved, Jesus sets the
example, which is why the Bible says,
"Let this mind be in you which was also
in Christ Jesus." Because who who being
in the form of God thought not robbery
to be equal with God, but made himself
of no reputation, and humbled himself,
and became obedient unto death. It's as
if the verse is telling us, see what
Jesus did?
Let that move you to do exactly as he
did.
And now, beloved, now we may read the
verse like this. Jeremiah 29:13, "And
you shall seek me and find me when you
search for me with all your heart."
Please understand
that we would not be searching for him
with all our heart if he did not first
demonstrate his love toward us with all
his heart. He was the merchant
who came and sold all that he had to
redeem us
which inspires a love in our hearts to
sell all that we have
for the pearl of great price. That's how
you understand it. Yeah. Yeah. Come on.
Look at this. Isaiah 55:6. Seek ye the
Lord while he may be found. Call upon
him while he is near. Let the wicked
forsake his way and the unrighteous man
his thoughts. And let him return unto
the Lord. And he will have mercy upon
him and to our God. For he will
abundantly pardon. For my thoughts are
not your thoughts, neither are your ways
my ways, sayeth the Lord. For as the
heavens are higher than the earth, so
are my ways higher than your ways, and
my thoughts than your thoughts. For as
the rain cometh down, and the snow from
heaven, and returnneeth not there, but
waterth the earth, and maketh it bring
forth in bud, that it may give seed to
the sewer, and bread to the eater, so
shall my word be that goeth forth out of
my mouth. It shall not return unto me
void, but it shall accomplish that which
I please, and it shall prosper in the
thing whereto I sent it. Please
understand that the word that came out
of the mouth of the father was the son.
He was the word. In the beginning was
the word and the word was with God. The
word came forth first unto us. And
beloved that word demonstrated his love
for us by giving up all that he had to
redeem us. And when we see that someone
said only by love is love awakened.
Only when we understand how much Jes the
divine merchant gave up for us. Only
when we comprehend and understand, wait
a minute, he gave up what I cannot even
fathom.
It is then,
it is then that me we may return to the
parable and read the second part,
the second aspect of this parable.
Again, the kingdom of heaven is like a
merchant looking for fine pearls. When
he found one of great value, he went
away and sold everything he had and
bought it. Now you're that merchant.
Now you're looking for the fine pearls.
Now you're looking for the pearls. Why?
Because you understand who the divine
merchant was. You understand what he
gave up for you.
You understand
the love
that he demonstrated towards you
and only when you understand that it is
then that you become the guy, the girl
looking for the pearl of great price.
Remember what we said earlier, the pearl
is not only a p, the pearl is a person.
You shall seek me and find me when you
search me with all your heart. Yeah. The
pearl is a person. So now we are looking
for the person Jesus Christ. He is the
pearl of great price.
Yes. Yes. Yes. The pearl is not only a
person, but the pearl is a place.
Listen. Matthew 6:33. But seek ye first
the kingdom of God and his
righteousness, and all these things
shall be added unto you. So beloved,
just as when Jesus was the merchant, the
pearl was me, the pearl was you, a pe a
a person, but the pearl was also a place
this earth. So in the second aspect of
the parable, the pearl, the merchant is
now you. The merchant is now me. And
what is the pearl? The pearl is Jesus,
but the pearl a a person, but the pearl
is also a place, and that is the kingdom
of God. Seek you first the kingdom of
God, and all these things shall be added
unto you. Seek me, and you shall find me
with all your hearts. And only then,
beloved, only then will we be moved to
sell all that we have.
Because now we see the value of the
great pearl.
Now we see the value of the son of God.
Now we see the value of the kingdom of
heaven.
Now we see what heaven gave up in
letting Jesus go. Because listen y'all,
heaven gave up.
Heaven let Jesus go.
When we see the love of divine
power
manifested toward us
then we can say then we can say like 2
Corinthians 8:9 then we can understand
though he was rich yet for your sakes he
became poor that you through his poverty
might be Rich
beloved, today's message
was simply to tell you something.
Simply to try to explain to you in in a
way that definitely falls short of the
depth
of love that God has for you.
But pastor,
you don't understand how how
distant I feel from God. You don't
understand how worthless I feel. You
don't understand how valueless I feel.
But I need you to understand,
Jesus is that merchant who is walking
around the store. And as and as everyone
else is walking by that that thing that
looks obviously worthless, he is the one
that says yes.
I'm willing to give up all for that
piece right there. This piece? You sure?
I'm sure. But this has no value.
I'm sure. Well, how much you willing to
give? Everything. Hold on. You don't
have to give everything. You can just
give a little. No.
I need that piece to know and understand
how valuable that piece is. If I pay a
little,
that peace
will be perceived as little value. So
the only way I can let that peace know
and let others know how valuable that
peace is to me, I must
pay all.
I must sell
all.
And beloved, it is it is all too often
the case
that because we don't really understand
just how much we are valued in God's
eyes,
we don't value ourselves.
We don't understand and therefore we
cannot receive the love of God that he
is trying to pour out and manifest to
us. It is my prayer today.
It is my prayer today
that as you think of this parable and
that heavenly merchant
who
yes
sold everything for you
and then left a will
and then left a will that is basically a
warning to anyone who would touch you do
you harm term.
The Ten Commandments
is God's
declaration
of touch him and see what happens.
Touch her and see what happens.
Have y'all ever thought about the law of
God like that before? Maybe you have.
Maybe you have.
But man, what what a
what a way to understand God's
protective love for us.
What a way to understand that when God
is telling you this, when he's saying to
you, "You better not lie. You better not
steal," he's not saying it in a vacuum.
He's saying it because
if you do that, you're doing it against
someone that I love.
And beloved, I don't know. We tend to we
tend to just take those commandments and
just look at it as a how can I how can I
demonstrate that I'm righteous before
God? How can I demonstrate that I'm
following his will? How can I
demonstrate that? See, I haven't done
this to anyone today. I haven't done
that to anyone today. But I need you to
understand, beloved,
I need you to to see those commandments
as God saying, "Here's how much I love
your neighbor, cuz he's mine. She's
mine. And here's how much I love you.
And anyone who violates these laws that
I have designed to protect you and comes
after you, they will answer to me. Wow.
Like what love? What love?
We love him because he first loved us.
But if we don't understand how he loved
us, if we don't understand the depth of
his love for us, if we don't understand
the power of his love for us, then our
love, our love back to him will be
surface.
If we want our love to be beyond the
surface, beloved, we got to understand
just how deep God's love is for us. Put
that five in the chat if you're saying
today, Lord, help me to understand in a
way that I never have. May this message
be the beginning. But Lord, help me to
meditate and really focus on how much
you actually love me.
And help me to see that the more I that
I focus on this, the more that I
understand. Whoa. You mean God just sent
a whole warning out to the world that
anybody that anybody that lies about me
that that takes what belongs to me has
to answer to him? What?
God is like my bodyguard.
God is like my protector. God is like my
my fortress.
H
I know. I see it.
I see it.
Praise God for all your decisions.
Praise God for all your decisions. Let
Let's pray, you guys. Let's pray. Let's
pray that this that this love story will
become a reality in our lives. That we
will begin to see and understand just
how much God loves us.
That that same love might be awakened in
our hearts. Let's pray. Heavenly Father,
thank you Lord for speaking through your
word to us today. Thank you, Lord, for
showing the example of the merchant man
that we might follow that example and
sell all that we have.
And Lord, help us to see that selling
all that we have is nothing in
comparison
to what we receive.
Just as Jesus selling all that he had
would seem to be an illogical sale, it
would seem to be that what he what he
was willing to give up for what was
worth little. He's now saying to us,
"What you have is worth little. Give it
up and I will give you beyond your
imagination." Please, Lord, speak to our
hearts. open our eyes and help us to see
the devil's lies,
the things that he makes us value to the
point of us being willing to lose
eternal life
to gain the world.
Open our eyes, Lord. Give us
understanding. Help us to see
and help us to experience
that unspeakable love you have for us.
Thank you, Lord Jesus, for hearing and
answering our prayers. Thank you for
every decision that has been made. Thank
you for all the fives in the chat, Lord,
for those that will be watching. Thank
you, Lord, for speaking and just
revealing your love, not just for people
who claim to follow you, but for the
whole world.
Thank you, Lord,
for hearing our prayer.
Thank you for demonstrating your love
toward us. We pray this in Jesus name.
Amen.
You guys, we're going to put in the um
in the chat the link for the afterglow
uh discussion. We of course welcome you
to uh to join us. Um,
if any of you are interested in um,
studying the Bible, uh, preparing for
baptism, we're going to go ahead and,
uh, invite you to, um, email Bibleworker
living.
You will see on the screen how you can
connect with living manner online
church, how you can submit prayer
requests, uh how you could follow us on
social media, and again um may God bless
you, may God keep you, may God cause his
face to shine upon you. And um may you
experience God's love in a new and
powerful way. God bless you and uh until
next week, may God keep you.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.